<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Autism News</title>
    <link>https://rcastonguay.github.io/autismfeeds/index.xml</link>
    <description>An RSS feed filtered by autism keywords.</description>
    <atom:link href="https://rcastonguay.github.io/autismfeeds/index.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 12:39:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Donald Triplett, ‘Case 1’ in the Study of Autism, Dies at 89</title>
      <link>https://www.nytimes.com/2023/06/18/obituaries/donald-triplett-dead.html</link>
      <description>He was widely considered the first person to be diagnosed with autism. His happy life later became the subject of a book and documentary.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 15:37:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weaponized heterogeneity only harms the most vulnerable autistic people</title>
      <link>https://www.spectrumnews.org/opinion/viewpoint/weaponized-heterogeneity-only-harms-the-most-vulnerable-autistic-people/</link>
      <description>"Autistic people as a group are heterogeneous, with a wide range of presentations, challenges, and support needs. That heterogeneity is commonly weaponized against more able autistic people, often by autism researchers or parents who wish to highlight the needs of their autistic children who have higher support needs. This tactic, however, can backfire and increase harm to the most vulnerable autistic people because it separates this group from the insights gained from autistic scholarship. Focusing on aspects of autistic experience that we all share may be more fruitful and lead more quickly to our shared goal of improved outcomes for all autistic people."</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A first in Canada: Playground communication boards for Montreal elementary school students with autism</title>
      <link>https://montreal.ctvnews.ca/a-first-in-canada-playground-communication-boards-for-montreal-elementary-school-students-with-autism-1.6449312</link>
      <description>For children on the autism spectrum, verbal communication can sometimes be difficult. To help children communicate their feelings and needs at recess, the Lester B. Pearson School Board is installing communication stations in the playgrounds of all of its elementary schools -- a first in Canada.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 23:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Langley girl with autism excluded from class field trip — until she wasn't</title>
      <link>https://vancouversun.com/news/local-news/langley-girl-with-autism-excluded-from-class-field-trip</link>
      <description>The school district reverses course after publicity on social media and in the local press</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 23:48:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>

