<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Autism News</title>
    <link>https://rcastonguay.github.io/autismfeeds/index.xml</link>
    <description>An RSS feed filtered by autism keywords.</description>
    <atom:link href="https://rcastonguay.github.io/autismfeeds/index.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 21:15:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>‘Employers should see autism as asset’: review seeks to break barriers at work</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/apr/02/employers-should-see-autism-as-asset-review-seeks-to-break-barriers-at-work</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Inquiry led by ex-minister Robert Buckland to examine UK support for neurodivergent people with aim of doubling employment rate&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A review attempting to identify and tackle the barriers &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/feb/06/autism-autistic-positive-neurodiversity" title=""&gt;autistic people face at work&lt;/a&gt; is being launched by the government, in an attempt to push companies to “reap the benefits of a neurodiverse workforce”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Robert Buckland, the former justice secretary who is father to an autistic adult, has been asked by the Department for Work and Pensions to lead the review designed to suggest how ministers could support employers attempting to &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global/2020/feb/03/autism-to-adhd-thinking-differently-about-recruitment" title=""&gt;recruit and retain autistic people&lt;/a&gt;. Autistic people currently have a very low rate of employment, with fewer than three in 10 in work. That compares with around half of all disabled people and 80% of non-disabled people.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/apr/02/employers-should-see-autism-as-asset-review-seeks-to-break-barriers-at-work"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 07:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autistic people are too often kept out of the workplace. That should end | Tom Pursglove and Robert Buckland</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/apr/02/autistic-people-often-kept-out-workplace-that-should-end</link>
      <description>Neurodiversity is too often regarded as a liability rather than the asset it is. Our plan is to change that&lt;p&gt;We know autistic people have one of the lowest employment rates of any disabled group in the UK, with fewer than three in 10 in work. Yet we continually hear of too many enthusiastic minds being locked out of the workplace because of a neurodiverse label. It is clear: change is needed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a situation that is not only hugely detrimental to those autistic people being kept of out of work but is also depriving employers of the known &lt;a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/journal-of-management-and-organization/article/advantages-and-challenges-of-neurodiversity-employment-in-organizations/E00D823A30F04CA4EA502014329C1CE9" title=""&gt;benefits of a neurodiverse workforce&lt;/a&gt;. Our autism employment review will take an in-depth look at how we can improve the employment prospects of autistic people.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/apr/02/autistic-people-often-kept-out-workplace-that-should-end"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 07:15:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Guardian view on Send provision: letting children down | Editorial</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/apr/02/the-guardian-view-on-send-provision-letting-children-down</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Record numbers of parents are fighting councils in court to get the support they need. They shouldn’t have to resort to this&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For parents whose children have special educational needs or disabilities (Send), getting help can resemble an adversarial battle. Over the last decade, parents have increasingly resorted to taking councils to court for failing to carry out assessments for education, health and care plans (EHCPs), or for issuing a plan that fails to recognise their child’s needs. Cases heard at tribunal have soared by &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/tribunal-statistics-quarterly-july-to-september-2022" title=""&gt;580%&lt;/a&gt; since 2011. Delayed support is harming children’s education and leaving many in distress. Parents who don’t have the time, money or confidence to fight their council, or who don’t speak English as a first language, are especially likely to see their children go without the help they need.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the Northamptonshire Chronicle recently submitted a freedom of information request to its local council, the newspaper found it had spent &lt;a href="https://www.northamptonchron.co.uk/news/politics/council/data-reveals-west-northants-council-has-spent-ps275000-of-taxpayers-money-fighting-disabled-childrens-parents-in-court-4016468" title=""&gt;£275,000&lt;/a&gt; on fighting such cases at tribunal. Most of these will be lost; &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=96%25+send+tribunal+cases&amp;amp;amp;oq=96%25+send+tribunal+cases&amp;amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57j33i160l3.5210j0j9&amp;amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;amp;ie=UTF-8" title=""&gt;95%&lt;/a&gt; go in parents’ favour. The cost of providing specialist support has the potential to bankrupt local authorities, one council treasurer &lt;a href="https://themj.co.uk/EXCLUSIVE-High-needs-spending-could-bankrupt-councils/220457" title=""&gt;recently wrote&lt;/a&gt;. Faced with rising demand for EHCPs, councils seem to be dragging out the process to save money. Similarly, huge waiting lists have led some &lt;a href="https://viewer.gutools.co.uk/society/2023/mar/26/children-put-at-risk-as-nhs-autism-assessments-are-cut-back" title=""&gt;NHS managers&lt;/a&gt; to drastically restrict initial autism assessments for children. Unless that is reversed, a greater number of children will go undiagnosed and miss out on support.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/apr/02/the-guardian-view-on-send-provision-letting-children-down"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 17:25:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘They tried to wipe it out’: the problem with talking about Asperger’s</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/apr/16/they-tried-to-wipe-it-out-the-problem-with-talking-about-aspergers</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The diagnostic terms for autism were overhauled 10 years ago. Experts, campaigners and autistic people reflect on these changes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chris Bonnello, 37, was diagnosed with Asperger syndrome in 2011. But these days he just says he’s autistic. “A lot of us did not want to let go originally, it was something that fitted us very nicely,” recalls the teacher turned autism advocate who runs a website called &lt;a href="https://autisticnotweird.com/"&gt;Autistic Not Weird&lt;/a&gt; from his home in Nottingham. “But it is better for autistic people if we are all recognised, acknowledged and appreciated together.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sarah Weston, 47, received a diagnosis of autism spectrum condition in 2019. Yet in daily life she describes herself as an “Aspie” – an informal, affectionate term for a person with Asperger syndrome. She doesn’t have the complex learning disabilities some autistic people do and which non-autistic people can think of when they hear autism. She says using Aspie or Asperger’s just helps outsiders understand what she’s like and clears up confusion. And she is certain, based on her cognitive and language abilities, that she would have received the Asperger’s label had she been diagnosed earlier.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/apr/16/they-tried-to-wipe-it-out-the-problem-with-talking-about-aspergers"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 09:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning-disabled and autistic people are being neglected and tortured. How much longer? | John Harris</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/apr/24/learning-disabled-autistic-neglect-uk-institutional-abuse</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Across the UK, revelations of institutional abuse keep mounting up, yet people are still being denied basic respect&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine a chain of scandals focused on a huge number of very vulnerable and fragile people. Picture a horrific mixture of mistreatment and neglect that is institutional, subjecting hundreds of people to completely the wrong “care”, and ensuring that many of them are effectively locked up, often for years. Then add an element that is even more horrific: seemingly endless acts of violence and torture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now think about the prospect of such stories piling up: by rights, you would expect some kind of tipping point. But in this case, the sheer number of scandals seems to somehow normalise them, so that even some of the most awful remain overlooked, even among people who think of themselves as progressive and socially concerned. We think we care, but our concern and empathy fall woefully short.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;John Harris is a Guardian columnist&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have an opinion on the issues raised in this article? If you would like to submit a response of up to 300 words by email to be considered for publication in our&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/tone/letters"&gt; letters&lt;/a&gt; section, please &lt;a href="mailto:guardian.letters@theguardian.com?body=Please%20include%20your%20name,%20full%20postal%20address%20and%20phone%20number%20with%20your%20letter%20below.%20Letters%20are%20usually%20published%20with%20the%20author%27s%20name%20and%20city/town/village.%20The%20rest%20of%20the%20information%20is%20for%20verification%20only%20and%20to%20contact%20you%20where%20necessary."&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/apr/24/learning-disabled-autistic-neglect-uk-institutional-abuse"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 07:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The distressing reality of ‘care’ for disabled young people | Letters</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/apr/26/the-distressing-reality-of-care-for-disabled-young-people</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Readers express their anger at the abuse of vulnerable people in care settings highlighted in an article by John Harris&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was both saddened and enraged to read John Harris’s article about the continuing abuse and torture of people with learning disabilities and autism (&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/apr/24/learning-disabled-autistic-neglect-uk-institutional-abuse" title=""&gt;Learning-disabled and autistic people are being neglected and tortured. How much longer?, 24 April&lt;/a&gt;). When will we realise that human services are not suitable fodder for money-making, shareholder-favouring companies? Although the fact that similar abuses have occurred in NHS systems in the past suggests other factors are at play.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/spe/about/philip-g-zimbardo" title=""&gt;Zimbardo prison experiment&lt;/a&gt; at Stanford University in the early 1970s showed how quickly people can fall into controlling or submissive roles if they do not have positive management and role models available, and if nobody dares blow the whistle. There are excellent services in some parts of the UK, with individualised support for people, but they are under constant pressure to cut costs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/apr/26/the-distressing-reality-of-care-for-disabled-young-people"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 16:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘I was given days to find myself a place to live’: autistic teenager on care home eviction</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/may/14/autistic-teenager-care-home-eviction-callum-mcdonald</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Callum McDonald describes how he and others coped when made to leave their settled homes by the private, profit-making owner&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was the most brutal start to the new year imaginable for Callum McDonald. The autistic teenager was given four weeks to leave the children’s home where he had lived for five years by the Outcomes First Group, one of the country’s largest for-profit care chains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“[Outcomes First] were completely indifferent. I was basically left to fend for myself,” said McDonald, 18, who was taken into care when he was eight years old. “I couldn’t find anywhere to stay because it happened so quickly. There wasn’t any transition period. It was just 28 days to be gone.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/may/14/autistic-teenager-care-home-eviction-callum-mcdonald"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 09:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pierre Novellie: ‘A heckler diagnosed my Asperger’s so fair play to him’</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2023/may/22/pierre-novellie-comedy-q-and-a-heckler-diagnosed-my-aspergers</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The comedian on his worst gig, preshow rituals and receiving an ASD diagnosis after an audience intervention&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did you start doing standup?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I always wondered if I was funny. Or rather if my private sense of humour, that I shared with very few people, would work on the public. That and being obsessed with comedy meant I was always going to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who inspired you when you were starting out?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I was inspired as a teenager by watching club comics perform on the various compilation shows of early 00s television (Live at the Store, Comedy Blue, etc) but also by people like Eddie Izzard and Dave Chappelle. When I read Frank Skinner’s descriptions of standup as the freest you can be, I was sold. I had to try it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2023/may/22/pierre-novellie-comedy-q-and-a-heckler-diagnosed-my-aspergers"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 08:42:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books with neurodivergent characters mark new chapter for publishers</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2023/jun/14/books-with-neurodivergent-characters-mark-new-chapter-for-publishers</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Children’s books featuring protagonists who are autistic or have ADHD are going to the highest bidder&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Children’s books that feature neurodiverse main characters are the latest publishing trend, experts have said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Publishers, which were previously reluctant to approach the subject, are increasingly seeking out realistic and explicitly neurodiverse protagonists, often by authors who are themselves neurodivergent.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2023/jun/14/books-with-neurodivergent-characters-mark-new-chapter-for-publishers"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 15:48:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The mother of neurodiversity: how Judy Singer changed the world</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/jul/05/the-mother-of-neurodiversity-how-judy-singer-changed-the-world</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1997 she transformed the way we think about human difference – and provided a name for a burgeoning movement&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Judy Singer is several thousand miles from her Australian home, on a two-week trip around the UK, which includes an onstage interview at Cambridge University and her receipt of an honorary fellowship from Birkbeck, University of London. Soon after we meet, she will do a round of sightseeing, then travel to meet relatives in Hungary. Her itinerary sounds very taxing, but her tiredness is combined with the pleasure of being belatedly honoured for her trailblazing work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We meet in a central London cafe where, for nearly three hours, she guides me through a life story that takes in the aftermath of the Holocaust, life in communist eastern Europe, her family’s migration to Australia, and a life that has mixed academia and activism with plenty of struggle and hardship. But what we talk about the most is neurodiversity, the concept she quietly introduced to the world in 1997.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/jul/05/the-mother-of-neurodiversity-how-judy-singer-changed-the-world"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 09:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Playing the drums is therapy in action | James Wood</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/jul/09/hitting-drums-therapy-drumming-teenagers-autism</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Research shows that drumming has benefits for teenagers with autism in terms of the brain, the body and attention levels&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s amazing that the young &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/theguardian/2010/sep/08/archive-keith-moon-found-dead" title=""&gt;Keith Moon&lt;/a&gt; got any education at all. At his Wembley school he was hyperactive, easily distracted, addicted to practical jokes – the sort of boy who, in the 1950s and 60s, got quickly spat out of the educational system. A friend later told Moon’s biographer: “You never felt: ‘One day he is going to be famous.’ You felt more likely that he was going to end up in prison.” Nowadays he’d be diagnosed with ADHD, drugged into discipline and eased into some of the gentler GCSEs. Fortunately for everyone else, he discovered drumming and joined &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/who" title=""&gt;the Who&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Playing the drums makes me think of Karl Kraus’s famous crack about psychoanalysis: it’s the mental illness for which it considers itself the therapy. Is drumming the symptom of lawless restlessness, showing off, a desire to make a very loud noise – or the cure for it? Recent research provides the answer: it’s the cure. A 2018 survey by Dr Ruth Lowry at the University of Essex suggested that drumming improved the motor skills and social health of kids with behavioural and emotional challenges. A new survey, led by the same researcher and organised by the &lt;a href="https://clemburkedrummingproject.org/" title=""&gt;Clem Burke Drumming Project&lt;/a&gt; (Burke is the terrific &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2023/jun/25/blondie-at-glastonbury-review-debbie-harry" title=""&gt;drummer for Blondie&lt;/a&gt;) goes further. The new study divided 36 teenagers with varieties of autism into two groups, one receiving drumming lessons for two months and one going without. The teenagers who played the drums showed a marked decrease in hyperactivity and inattention.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/jul/09/hitting-drums-therapy-drumming-teenagers-autism"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 07:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We were inundated’: creating pioneering homes for autistic young adults</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/10/we-were-inundated-creating-pioneering-homes-for-autistic-young-adults</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the success of Linden Farm, the Simon Trust helps families create specialised local residences for their adult children with highly complex needs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parents across the UK are forming partnerships with local councils to build pioneering supported-living homes for their autistic children with high needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With growing numbers of parents increasingly unable to find suitable, safe and secure residential accommodation for their young adult children – and cash-strapped councils having to pay exorbitant costs when already expensive placements break down – the two are coming together to forge a solution.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/10/we-were-inundated-creating-pioneering-homes-for-autistic-young-adults"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 05:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jason Arday: he learned to talk at 11 and read at 18 – then became Cambridge's youngest Black professor</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/11/jason-arday-cambridge-university-youngest-black-professor</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Diagnosed with autism as a child, Arday found his voice through speech therapy and his mother’s unflagging support. Now he is using it with the same tenacity that saw him run 30 marathons in 35 days&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jason Arday believes in destiny. The University of Cambridge’s youngest Black professor, he joined its faculty of education in March 2023, at 37. Before then, he had been a professor at Glasgow and Durham universities; published three books of academic work, mainly focusing on race and education; and, most importantly to him, raised more than £5m by doing charity work. All of this he has squeezed into a time period where he was learning to navigate the world with neurodivergence; Arday didn’t speak until he was 11 and couldn’t read or write until the age of 18.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s an unlikely story, he concedes, one that has made headlines and changed his life irrevocably. But he believes he was always going to do something great. “I knew I was destined to do something,” he says with a smile. “But I didn’t know it’d be this, admittedly.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/11/jason-arday-cambridge-university-youngest-black-professor"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 09:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK children waiting 16 months on average for ADHD and autism screening – study</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/17/uk-children-waiting-16-months-on-average-for-adhd-and-autism-screening-study</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Exclusive: Belfast has worst data, with typical wait of five years to be seen, against Nice guidance of 13-week maximum&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Children with suspected ADHD and autism are waiting as long as seven years for treatment on the NHS, as the health service struggles to manage a surge in demand during a crisis in child mental health.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experts said “inhumane” waits are putting a generation of neurodiverse children at risk of mental illness as they are “pushed to the back of a very long queue” for children and adolescent mental health services (Camhs).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/17/uk-children-waiting-16-months-on-average-for-adhd-and-autism-screening-study"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 05:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autism could be seen as part of personality for some diagnosed, experts say</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/31/autism-could-be-seen-as-part-of-personality-for-some-diagnosed-experts-say</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Autism without intellectual disabilities could be reframed as human ‘variability’ rather than medical condition, says sociologist&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/31/adults-finally-diagnosed-autism-adhd"&gt;‘I recognised myself for the first time’: the adults finally diagnosed as autistic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;With a seven-fold rise in diagnoses of autism in the past 20 years in the UK, studies showing one in 36 children could be on the spectrum and waiting lists for help and support at record highs, awareness of neurodiversity has never been so high.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, key voices are arguing that some autistic people could no longer be considered as having a disability at all. Instead, their autism could be regarded as part of their personality.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/31/autism-could-be-seen-as-part-of-personality-for-some-diagnosed-experts-say"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 17:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘I recognised myself for the first time’: the adults finally diagnosed as autistic</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/31/adults-finally-diagnosed-autism-adhd</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Antoinette Monks was diagnosed with autism and ADHD at 71, while Debra Brisch got her diagnosis at 68. Both say it was life-changing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/31/autism-could-be-seen-as-part-of-personality-for-some-diagnosed-experts-say"&gt;Autism could be seen as part of personality for some diagnosed, experts say&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Antoinette Monks was diagnosed with autism and probable inattentive ADHD last year, at 71 years old.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I have always known that I was different and always let everyone down but I didn’t know why,” she said. “That ‘not knowing why’ has haunted me throughout my life but it seemed impossible that I would ever find out why I behaved as I did.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/31/adults-finally-diagnosed-autism-adhd"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 17:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School phone ban would hit autistic children the hardest | Letter</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/aug/03/school-phone-ban-would-hit-autistic-children-the-hardest</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Barring smartphones from schools – as proposed by the UN – could leave autistic pupils feeling lost and overwhelmed, warns &lt;strong&gt;Carrie Myshkin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I didn’t grow up with a smartphone at school. I’m 36. I had to make do with portable CD players and books. Nowadays, my phone is a vital part of my life. As an autistic person, it helps me play music and meditate, and generally shut out some of the overwhelmingness of the outside world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That could have helped me so much, had it been available to me when I was at school. I can read and listen to books on my phone, both of which would, again, have been massively helpful to me at school.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/aug/03/school-phone-ban-would-hit-autistic-children-the-hardest"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 17:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smartphones aren’t the answer for all autistic people | Letters</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/aug/06/smartphones-arent-the-answer-for-all-autistic-people</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elaine Bennett&lt;/strong&gt; believes the increasing use of technology is only serving to further isolate some people in a neurotypical world&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I disagree with your correspondent (&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/aug/03/school-phone-ban-would-hit-autistic-children-the-hardest" title=""&gt;Letters, 3 August&lt;/a&gt;) that a ban on mobile phones in schools will impact pupils with autistic spectrum disorder (ASD) negatively. People with ASD are already at risk of being pushed away from contact with other people and offered technology as an answer to every need.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have ASD and I’m increasingly finding that the answers to any difficulties I have are all technological ones, often involving a smartphone that I don’t have. Having ASD does not equate to preferring to not speak to other humans. I feel that technology is being used as another way to silo people out of a neurotypical world.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/aug/06/smartphones-arent-the-answer-for-all-autistic-people"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 15:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Splitting York autistic twins may have unwanted outcome - charity</title>
      <link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-york-north-yorkshire-66163563?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=KARANGA</link>
      <description>Reuben and Jasper, who are both autistic, have been given places at two different schools.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 03:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vernon grad powers through autism to achieve his dreams</title>
      <link>https://vernonmatters.ca/2023/07/03/vernon-grad-powers-through-autism-to-achieve-his-dreams/</link>
      <description>When Ethan Hammerton was two and a half years old his mother Shanda wondered if she would ever hear her son say “mom” again. Shanda Hammerton had a normal pregnancy and Ethan was a healthy baby who developed normally until he was about 14 months old. At 26 months, Ethan had a screening and the family was told that “he is autistic.”</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>

