<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Autism News</title>
    <link>https://rcastonguay.github.io/autismfeeds/index.xml</link>
    <description>An RSS feed filtered by autism keywords.</description>
    <atom:link href="https://rcastonguay.github.io/autismfeeds/index.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 21:21:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>How the rise of autism and ADHD fractured Australia’s schools</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/apr/29/how-the-rise-of-autism-and-adhd-fractured-australias-schools</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost a million Australian schoolchildren now have a disability – that’s one in four enrolments. Parents, teachers and advocates say education is at crisis point&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/apr/29/revealed-private-school-students-reap-thousands-more-than-public-students-in-disability-funding"&gt;Revealed: Private school students reap thousands more than public students in disability funding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Analysis: &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/apr/29/why-the-guardian-is-investigating-the-deep-failings-in-australias-school-system"&gt;Why the Guardian is investigating the deep failings in Australia’s school system&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every morning before school, Emerson Cook would ask his mum to check the weather. If it was raining she knew her then five-year-old would be anxious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“He was always worried about rain,” Alicia Cook says. “And if the weather forecast was rain, I would be anxious too …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed"&gt;Sign up for Guardian Australia’s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/apr/29/how-the-rise-of-autism-and-adhd-fractured-australias-schools"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 15:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Students as young as five with disabilities disproportionately suspended from Australia’s schools</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/may/01/australia-schools-students-with-disabilities-disproportionately-suspended</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Guardian Australia data analysis shows suspensions are increasing in most states. Students with disabilities are overrepresented&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/apr/29/how-the-rise-of-autism-and-adhd-fractured-australias-schools"&gt;How the rise of autism and ADHD fractured Australia’s schools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Analysis: &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/apr/29/why-the-guardian-is-investigating-the-deep-failings-in-australias-school-system"&gt;Why the Guardian is investigating the deep failings in Australia’s school system&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thousands of students with a disability, including those as young as five, are receiving repeated suspensions from Australian schools amid calls from advocates for an overhaul of the education system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Guardian Australia analysis of school suspension data shows the number of students being suspended from schools is rising in most states, including among primary school aged students.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed"&gt;Sign up for Guardian Australia’s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/may/01/australia-schools-students-with-disabilities-disproportionately-suspended"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 15:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six-year-old student restrained in infant high chair at NSW school, family claims</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/may/02/six-year-old-student-restrained-in-infant-high-chair-at-nsw-school-family-claims</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The boy, who has autism and Down syndrome, was photographed in the restraint for a social media post, his guardian says&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/apr/29/why-the-guardian-is-investigating-the-deep-failings-in-australias-school-system"&gt;Why the Guardian is investigating the deep failings in Australia’s school system&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/may/01/australia-schools-students-with-disabilities-disproportionately-suspended"&gt;Students as young as five with disabilities disproportionately suspended from Australia’s schools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;morning and afternoon news emails&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A six-year-old boy &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/apr/29/how-the-rise-of-autism-and-adhd-fractured-australias-schools"&gt;with autism&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/downs-syndrome"&gt;Down syndrome&lt;/a&gt; was strapped into an infant’s high chair at a New South Wales primary school regularly over an eight-month period, his family allege, with the case now the subject of a complaint to the Australian Human Rights Commission.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neville Williams’ aunt and guardian, Karla Bedford, said she first learned that the six-year-old was being physically restrained at Tingha public school in northern NSW after the school posted a photo of him in the chair on social media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed"&gt;Sign up for Guardian Australia’s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/may/02/six-year-old-student-restrained-in-infant-high-chair-at-nsw-school-family-claims"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I’m going to be blunt: our neurotypical school system is the problem | Elly Desmarchelier</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/commentisfree/2024/may/02/im-going-to-be-blunt-our-neurotypical-school-system-is-the-problem</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Classrooms must be places of learning not conflict, where each child’s individual needs are understood and supported &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s me, hi, I’m the problem, it’s me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As an autistic person, that’s certainly the way it feels at the moment. Autism seems to be to blame for every issue.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/commentisfree/2024/may/02/im-going-to-be-blunt-our-neurotypical-school-system-is-the-problem"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carolann Jackson obituary</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/may/05/carolann-jackson-obituary</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend Carolann Jackson, who has died aged 80, was a campaigner and advocate on behalf of people with Asperger syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the first part of her adult life she worked in the music business, managing bands. But her focus changed after the birth of her daughter, Nita. Early on, Carolann noticed that her daughter appeared to behave differently to other children of her age.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/may/05/carolann-jackson-obituary"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 15:47:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The truth about ADHD and autism: how many people have it, what causes it, and why are diagnoses soaring?</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/01/the-truth-about-adhd-and-autism-how-many-people-have-it-what-causes-it-and-why-are-diagnoses-soaring</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Growing awareness about ADHD and autism is reshaping thinking in science, society and medicine. Scientists explain what’s behind the rise – and the best ways to improve neurodivergent lives &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was in the mid 90s that neurodiversity as a formal concept and a rights movement began to emerge. Aided by the internet, autistic people and those with other conditions were able to connect and began sharing their experiences: what they had in common, how their lives differed. A recurring theme was how many felt marginalised, pushed out of a society that embraced only typical ways of being in the world. The phrase “neurological diversity” cropped up in their discussions, which along with “neurodiversity” appeared in magazine articles later that decade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neurodiversity has clear parallels with biodiversity. It champions difference and the validity of individuals. It holds that a vaguely defined majority can be described as neurotypical, with brains that operate in a broadly similar way. Others, meanwhile, are neurodivergent, with brains that are built and work somewhat differently.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/01/the-truth-about-adhd-and-autism-how-many-people-have-it-what-causes-it-and-why-are-diagnoses-soaring"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 06:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I’d do anything to make my autistic daughter happy – but I feel like a walking mum-fail</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/01/id-do-anything-to-make-my-autistic-daughter-happy-but-i-feel-like-a-walking-mum-fail</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is an intense emotional strain involved with parenting a neurodivergent child with mental health issues. But we will do whatever it takes to understand her brain&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“There’s something wrong with me!” my seven-year-old daughter sobbed, back in 2018. “Honestly, there isn’t,” I said, giving her a hug. “You’re just a bit sensitive, a bit anxious.” I wanted to be the reassuring parent, the mum who makes everything all right. But I was having the opposite effect on her: I was underplaying her distress, and it scared her, and shook her faith in me. How could she get any help if I didn’t accept there was a problem?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the time her dad and I didn’t know our daughter was autistic. She was certainly not the easiest to manage, but she was also funny, bright, imaginative and popular at school. And although we were aware that she had intrusive thoughts, separation and sensory issues, a nasty phobia and difficulty controlling her emotions, her teachers, our GP, relatives and friends told us not to worry too much. “She’s a character! She’ll be&amp;nbsp;fine.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/01/id-do-anything-to-make-my-autistic-daughter-happy-but-i-feel-like-a-walking-mum-fail"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 12:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avoid noise, play mini golf, cast your net wide: Ellie Middleton’s neurodivergent dating guide</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/02/avoid-noise-play-mini-golf-cast-your-net-wide-ellie-middletons-neurodivergent-dating-guide</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From making small talk to missing social cues, the road to romance can be rocky for those with ADHD and autism. Here are some tips for how to navigate it&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is safe to say that, when it comes to dating and relationships, I’ve never had an easy ride. I’ve always been the one who cares more, the one who is “too intense” and the one who winds up getting hurt. I wear my heart on my sleeve and, as a relatively newly diagnosed autistic woman with ADHD, there are two words that have followed me around and haunted me throughout my entire life: “too much”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Until recently, being “too much” was a&amp;nbsp;source of great shame. I spent my teenage years and early 20s trying to navigate dating and relationships while missing a key piece of information about myself – that I was an autistic ADHDer. I didn’t know that I was prone to feeling things much more deeply than most people, or that masking made me a chronic people pleaser. I didn’t know that I had a social disability, or that my dopamine-seeking brain might look for stimulation from problematic places (or people). I thought that my too much-ness was just a result of being unlovable, broken or a “bad dater”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/02/avoid-noise-play-mini-golf-cast-your-net-wide-ellie-middletons-neurodivergent-dating-guide"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 06:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In a household with autism and ADHD, socks are meaningful</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/02/in-a-household-with-autism-and-adhd-socks-are-meaningful</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Too scratchy, too loose or simply gone awol, every neurodiverse family needs a sock strategiser&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The doorbell goes and I bounce down the stairs to receive a delivery. Relief washes over me as I rip open the brown packaging and the new socks spill out. This is more than a delivery of socks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my household, with a mixture of autism and ADHD, socks are meaningful. We can be forgetful and disorganised, but also hyperfocused and incredibly productive. The thinking in this house can be literal, linear and precise; and in contrast, spontaneous energetic and free. None of us want to apply ourselves to something that seems boring, and socks are really boring.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/02/in-a-household-with-autism-and-adhd-socks-are-meaningful"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 12:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘I can only love 100% or 0%’: Chris Packham on navigating a neurodiverse relationship</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/03/i-can-only-love-100-or-0-chris-packham-on-navigating-a-neurodiverse-relationship</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The naturalist and his neurotypical partner – and other couples with ADHD and autism – open up about how they have learned to love and be loved&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chris: &lt;/strong&gt;I can’t love Charlotte 99.9%. That doesn’t exist in my world. I can only offer Charlotte 100% of myself – or 0%. The 100% commitment, which has previously been suffocating in relationships, is something which I hope gives Charlotte a degree of&amp;nbsp;security.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/03/i-can-only-love-100-or-0-chris-packham-on-navigating-a-neurodiverse-relationship"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 06:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘I was terrified of the tea round’: the small changes that can help neurodivergent people thrive at work</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/04/i-was-terrified-of-the-tea-round-the-small-changes-that-can-help-neurodivergent-people-thrive-at-work</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Workers with ADHD and autism bring impressive skills and dedication to their jobs, but face challenges neurotypical employers may not consider. A few key adjustments can be transformative&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To the outside world, Kat Brown was a professional success. What her colleagues didn’t know, however, was how much effort it was costing her. “I had this underlying kind of whirring voice in my head of ‘you’re not good enough, you’re not normal, you need to try five times harder than everybody else’,” says Brown, author of the ADHD memoir It’s Not A Bloody Trend. “The only way I could calm that down was with alcohol, and along with booze, coffee. It was the way I lassoed my brain into doing what I wanted.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That meant downing up to nine americanos a day, unwinding with drinks after work – and sometimes bursting into exhausted tears when she got home. Only when she was diagnosed&amp;nbsp;with ADHD at 37, shortly after quitting her job in the media and going freelance, did everything begin to make sense. Some people with ADHD, she explains, find caffeine helps stabilise rather than stimulate an already whirring&amp;nbsp;mind. Meanwhile her anxiety, she thinks, reflected a sense that she was different and a terror of being somehow&amp;nbsp;exposed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/04/i-was-terrified-of-the-tea-round-the-small-changes-that-can-help-neurodivergent-people-thrive-at-work"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 06:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Find people who understand you and be kind to yourself’: an expert guide to living well with neurodiversity</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/04/be-kind-to-yourself-an-expert-guide-to-living-well-with-neurodiversity</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A GP, psychologist, nutritionist and fitness instructor give their advice on how to live healthily and happily with ADHD and autism&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr Heidi Phillips, clinical advisor on neurodiversity for the Royal College of GPs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/04/be-kind-to-yourself-an-expert-guide-to-living-well-with-neurodiversity"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 12:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘He is thriving now; a different child’: the battle to educate neurodivergent pupils</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/05/he-is-thriving-now-a-different-child-the-battle-to-educate-neurodivergent-pupils</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Parents of children with additional needs in England endure endless bureaucracy, but help is out there – and it is worth the fight&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Blaine was six he was diagnosed with dyspraxia. Then, as he neared the end of his time at his West Midlands primary school, the class teacher suggested that there might be a lot more going on. “Anything that disrupted his routine was an absolute nightmare,” says Joanne Terry of her son, who is now 14. “He was behind his peers by at least two or three years. His teacher could see when he was losing his concentration. So we decided to get an assessment for autism.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That was the beginning of a kind of Kafkaesque saga that will be familiar to hundreds of thousands of families in England whose lives involve both neurodivergence and the world of Special Educational Needs and Disabilities, or&amp;nbsp;Send.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/05/he-is-thriving-now-a-different-child-the-battle-to-educate-neurodivergent-pupils"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 06:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I’m autistic – and I couldn’t be happier than when I’m lost in a huge crowd</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/05/im-autistic-and-i-couldnt-be-happier-than-when-im-lost-in-a-huge-crowd</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whereas in a small group I freeze, surrounded by a mass of people&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;at Glastonbury or the football, I lose all my inhibitions and feel that I fit into the human race&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like many autistic people, I often feel uncomfortable around others. Put me in a one-to-one and I freeze. In a group of people around a table I say nothing – and leave as soon as possible. But give me a huge, surging crowd and I couldn’t be&amp;nbsp;happier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It confuses people, who assume I’d hate crowds and be agoraphobic; more people equals more pain. But it couldn’t be less true. I’ve been going to Manchester City matches for more than 20 years. And there is nowhere I’m happier than in the away end, right at the front, locked in with a mass of people, chanting, singing the songs, screaming my head off.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/jun/05/im-autistic-and-i-couldnt-be-happier-than-when-im-lost-in-a-huge-crowd"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 12:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Austin review – this funny, big-hearted comedy will leave you wanting another season</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/article/2024/jun/09/austin-review-tv-series-abc-michael-theo-love-on-the-spectrum</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Love on the Spectrum star Michael Theo is wonderful as an autistic man who tracks down his hapless father and his wife&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This very funny and sharply executed comedy series has a big heart, underneath a thick layer of dry, cheeky humour. The eponymous Austin is a 28-year-old autistic man, played with understated but thoroughly irresistible charm by Michael Theo, who was one of the stars of the ABC &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2022/sep/05/love-on-the-spectrum-australian-team-behind-us-version-of-beloved-show-win-three-emmy-awards"&gt;reality show Love on the Spectrum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the series begins, Austin’s preparing to introduce himself to his biological father, Julian, a British children’s book author who is unaware of his existence. Julian is perfectly brought to life by another irresistible, albeit more petulant, performance from British comedian Ben Miller.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/article/2024/jun/09/austin-review-tv-series-abc-michael-theo-love-on-the-spectrum"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 20:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mealtimes can be daunting for a child who is autistic or has ADHD. Here are five ways to support them | Stella Boyd-Ford and Clare Dix for the Conversation</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/article/2024/jun/18/mealtimes-can-be-daunting-for-a-child-who-is-autistic-or-has-adhd-here-are-five-ways-to-support-them</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From identifying ‘safe foods’ to having a designated plate and cutlery, there are a few practical ways to make mealtimes more manageable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gathering as a family for a meal can serve several purposes, from social connection to nutrition. But this can also make eating and mealtimes tricky to manage when someone in the family is neurodivergent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many autistic children and children with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) display what has been called “&lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S1750946719300595?via%3Dihub"&gt;abnormal feeding behaviours&lt;/a&gt;”. Children may develop these behaviours as a way to cope with the complex task of mealtimes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Food selectivity, where a child has a small range of preferred foods and limited variety. For example, children choosing only grain-based or dairy foods, such as noodles and yoghurt, or toast and cheese.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Strong preferences in how food is prepared and presented, including brands or tableware used – such as only accepting hot chips from one source, or only being able to use one bowl or fork.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hypersensitivity to textures, such as needing foods to be very crunchy or preferring foods that are smooth like puree.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overeating or undereating due to differences in how children understand and respond to body signals, a sense known as “&lt;a href="https://kids.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/frym.2021.558246#:%7E:text=Interoception%20means%20sensing%20internal%20signals,when%20you%20need%20the%20toilet."&gt;interoception&lt;/a&gt;”. This can mean they go long periods without eating, or graze throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Avoiding eating with others, choosing instead to eat in the lounge room or their bedroom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inflexibility around mealtime routines due to a drive for consistency and sameness to feel safe. This means eating in different places, at different times, or having unfamiliar foods becomes challenging.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Difficulty transitioning to mealtimes due to &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7851038/#:%7E:text=Hyperfocus%2C%20broadly%20and%20anecdotally%20speaking,is%20particularly%20fun%20or%20interesting."&gt;hyperfocus&lt;/a&gt; on a preferred task.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/article/2024/jun/18/mealtimes-can-be-daunting-for-a-child-who-is-autistic-or-has-adhd-here-are-five-ways-to-support-them"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Sensory Needs During the Holidays</title>
      <link>https://www.autismbc.ca/blog/sensory-friendly-holidays/</link>
      <description>This time of year is filled with an abundance of sensory stimuli unique to the holidays. The lights are brighter, the scents are richer, the food is special, and every day it seems like there is something else to do. For those of us with sensory processing challenges, it can easily become too much. Here are some tips from both a parent’s and autistic adult’s perspective to make this holiday season a little more sensory-friendly.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holidays</title>
      <link>https://www.autismspeaks.org/holidays</link>
      <description>Holidays can be both the best of times and the worst of times for autistic individuals and their families. Changes in routine, increased social demands, crowds and gatherings, new activities, sensory overloaded events, unfamiliar foods and other out-of-the-ordinary experiences can all present challenges.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>

