<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Autism News</title>
    <link>https://rcastonguay.github.io/autismfeeds/index.xml</link>
    <description>An RSS feed filtered by autism keywords.</description>
    <atom:link href="https://rcastonguay.github.io/autismfeeds/index.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 03:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Why police are accused of radicalising an autistic teenager – podcast</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/audio/2024/feb/19/australia-police-autistic-teenager-islamic-state-fixation-operation-full-story-podcast</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When a lonely and impressionable teenager became fixated on Islamic State, police began an operation that ended up further radicalising him. At just 14, the boy was then charged with terrorism offences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Courts and justice reporter &lt;strong&gt;Nino Bucci &lt;/strong&gt;tells &lt;strong&gt;Patrick Keneally &lt;/strong&gt;how and why police targeted the vulnerable teenager, and the questions the case raises about the authorities’ role in the deradicalisation process&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;You can support the Guardian at &lt;a href="http://theguardian.com/fullstorysupport"&gt;theguardian.com/fullstorysupport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can subscribe for free to Guardian Australia’s daily &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story"&gt;news podcast Full Story&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/au/podcast/full-story/id1482061243"&gt;Apple Podcasts&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/7GJod4EyoLywB1AW6zrSHh"&gt; Spotify&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://podcasts.google.com/feed/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cudGhlZ3VhcmRpYW4uY29tL2F1c3RyYWxpYS1uZXdzL3Nlcmllcy9mdWxsLXN0b3J5L3BvZGNhc3QueG1s?sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwjogPTcoIj_AhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAQ&amp;amp;hl=en-AU"&gt;Google Podcasts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read more:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/audio/2024/feb/19/australia-police-autistic-teenager-islamic-state-fixation-operation-full-story-podcast"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 14:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Guardian view on the special needs crisis: children don’t deserve this chaos | Editorial</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2024/feb/19/the-guardian-view-on-the-special-needs-crisis-children-dont-deserve-this-chaos</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By failing to adequately fund their own policy, ministers have created a destructive standoff between families, councils and schools&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A decade after David Cameron’s coalition government &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/teacher-network/teacher-blog/2014/feb/10/special-educational-needs-sen-reforms-five-things"&gt;overhauled provision&lt;/a&gt; for children with special educational needs and disabilities (Send) in England, it has never been clearer that the system is in crisis. A raft of measures designed to appeal to parents, by promising them greater influence over their children’s education, has resulted in a destructive standoff between families, schools and councils – because ministers failed to adequately fund their own policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead of the choices that were offered, parents of pupils who, for a range of reasons, are not thriving in mainstream classrooms, have been forced to fight for the resources that local authorities must provide to enable them to access education. &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/mar/26/children-put-at-risk-as-nhs-autism-assessments-are-cut-back"&gt;Long waiting times&lt;/a&gt; for NHS autism assessments, combined with &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2024/feb/18/hundreds-of-children-with-special-needs-wait-a-year-for-support-in-england"&gt;delays&lt;/a&gt; in issuing education, health and care plans (EHCPs) – the documents that set out children’s entitlements – mean that thousands of families are stuck. Even where plans have been agreed, there are many instances in which pupils do not receive the placement or support that they ought to guarantee. Families are left trapped, knowing that needs are not being met but unable to remedy what can turn into a damaging experience of exclusion from education.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2024/feb/19/the-guardian-view-on-the-special-needs-crisis-children-dont-deserve-this-chaos"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 18:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some NHS centres twice as likely to diagnose adults as autistic, study finds</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/04/some-nhs-centres-twice-as-likely-to-diagnose-adults-as-autistic-study-finds</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Landmark research suggests people have an 85% chance of positive assessment at some centres in England and 35% in others&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/04/uk-increase-autism-diagnoses-neurodiversity"&gt;What’s behind the increase in autism diagnoses?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adults awaiting an autism diagnosis face a postcode lottery in England, with some NHS centres more than twice as likely as others to give a positive assessment of the condition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Landmark research from University College London (UCL) suggests people have an 85% chance of being diagnosed as autistic in some centres compared with a 35% chance in others.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/04/some-nhs-centres-twice-as-likely-to-diagnose-adults-as-autistic-study-finds"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 14:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s behind the UK’s increase in autism diagnoses?</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/04/uk-increase-autism-diagnoses-neurodiversity</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Experts are undecided about whether there is overdiagnosis or whether more children are autistic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/04/some-nhs-centres-twice-as-likely-to-diagnose-adults-as-autistic-study-finds"&gt;Some NHS centres twice as likely to diagnose adults as autistic, study finds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autism is a condition in a state of slow flux. In &lt;a href="https://acamh.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jcpp.13505"&gt;2021, a study&lt;/a&gt; found a 787% rise in the number of diagnoses between 1998 and 2018 in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Increases in diagnoses have been a feature of autism for almost as long as it has been a recognised condition: &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4467195/#:~:text=In%20the%20mid%2D1980s%2C%20researchers,%E2%80%9Cpre%2Depidemic%E2%80%9D%20period."&gt;80 years ago&lt;/a&gt;, autism was thought to affect one in 2,500&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;children. That has gradually increased and now &lt;a href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lanepe/article/PIIS2666-7762(23)00045-5/fulltext"&gt;one in 36 children&lt;/a&gt; are believed to have autism spectrum disorder (ASD).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/04/uk-increase-autism-diagnoses-neurodiversity"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 14:08:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autistic pupils in England denied right to education as absenteeism surges, says charity</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/05/autistic-pupils-in-england-denied-right-to-education-as-absenteeism-surges-says-charity</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Research shows 166% rise of pupils missing one-tenth or more of school term&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/05/he-hates-failing-mother-describes-lack-of-help-for-autistic-son"&gt;‘He hates failing’: mother describes lack of help for autistic son&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autistic pupils are being denied their basic right to education, a leading charity has warned, as figures reveal the number persistently off school has increased by 166% in four years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The research shows that more than a quarter of autistic children in England – 51,000 out of about 200,000 children – are persistently absent, meaning they have missed 10% or more of the school term.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/05/autistic-pupils-in-england-denied-right-to-education-as-absenteeism-surges-says-charity"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 12:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘He hates failing’: mother describes lack of help for autistic son</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/05/he-hates-failing-mother-describes-lack-of-help-for-autistic-son</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kirsti Hadley’s son, 12, had been looking forward to a new school but became burnt out and anxious&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/05/autistic-pupils-in-england-denied-right-to-education-as-absenteeism-surges-says-charity"&gt;Autistic pupils in England denied right to education as absenteeism surges, says charity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kirsti Hadley is still reeling from how quickly her autistic son’s education has crumbled and how she cannot access help to get him back on track.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since November 2022, her 12-year-old son has only managed to spend a few hours a week at Varndean school in Brighton.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/05/he-hates-failing-mother-describes-lack-of-help-for-autistic-son"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 12:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new understanding: how research into autism is evolving</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/08/research-autism-evolving-transforming-lives-social-communication-therapy-drugs-trials</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With an emphasis on working with autistic people to design interventions, pathways are opening up through social communication therapy and drug trials&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kirsty Orton didn’t mind whether her baby was autistic or not – she just wanted her 12-month-old to enjoy being with his mummy: to notice her when she came into the room. To meet her eye when she talked to him and to be able to communicate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“All I wanted to do was be able to connect and bond with Fynn,” she said. “But when your baby looks everywhere else in the room except at you and stays in their own zone, like you’re completely unimportant to them, it’s upsetting in a way that I struggle to put into words.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/08/research-autism-evolving-transforming-lives-social-communication-therapy-drugs-trials"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 08:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Labour could rescue children from this endless series of educational crises | Letters</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2024/mar/14/how-labour-could-rescue-children-from-this-endless-series-of-educational-crises</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doreen Worthington &lt;/strong&gt;says&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;a new Education Reform Act is needed and lists what an incoming government could do&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The autism crisis (&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/05/autistic-pupils-in-england-denied-right-to-education-as-absenteeism-surges-says-charity"&gt;Autistic pupils in England denied right to education as absenteeism surges, says charity, 5 March&lt;/a&gt;) is the latest in a long list of crises in English schools that the Guardian has reported on recently, including the children’s mental health crisis, the teacher recruitment and retention crisis, the headteacher retention crisis, the absenteeism crisis, the Ofsted intimidation crisis, the crisis of children not being toilet trained or knowing how to brush their teeth, the literacy crisis, the maths crisis and now the special educational needs and disabilities (Send) crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is it not time that someone (a future Labour government perhaps) started to join the dots and realise that a new Education Reform Act is needed to rescue our children from this crisis in education? They could start with a snappy election slogan – “Education, education, education” for example – and a commitment to bringing back Sure Start centres, funding nursery and early years education properly, reversing almost all the Gove-era ideological changes to the curriculum and testing regimes, bringing back the arts, humanities, sport and extracurricular activities that schools can no longer afford or find time for, funding and reforming Send provision, investing properly in child and adolescent mental health services, abolishing Ofsted and replacing it with his majesty’s inspectors, introducing a fair salary system and, finally, abolishing multi-academy trusts and bringing all schools back under properly funded local education authority control.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2024/mar/14/how-labour-could-rescue-children-from-this-endless-series-of-educational-crises"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 18:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vulnerable man pleads with UK government to block extradition to US</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/law/2024/mar/15/diogo-santos-coelho-pleads-uk-block-us-extradition-cybercrime-raidforums</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Diogo Santos Coelho from Portugal faces a 52-year sentence for alleged cybercrime relating to RaidForums site&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A vulnerable autistic man is pleading with the UK government to block his extradition to the US on cybercrime charges where he faces a 52-year sentence for alleged offending that began when he was a child.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diogo Santos Coelho, who has been assessed as at very high risk of suicide, said he had been groomed and exploited online by adults from the age of 14 into committing the alleged crimes, which relate to the website RaidForums.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the UK and Ireland, &lt;a href="https://www.samaritans.org/"&gt;Samaritans&lt;/a&gt; can be contacted on freephone 116 123, or email &lt;a href="mailto:jo@samaritans.org"&gt;jo@samaritans.org&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="mailto:jo@samaritans.ie"&gt;jo@samaritans.ie&lt;/a&gt;. In the US, the &lt;a href="https://suicidepreventionlifeline.org/"&gt;National Suicide Prevention Lifeline&lt;/a&gt; is at 988 or chat for support. You can also text HOME to 741741 to connect with a crisis text line counselor. In Australia, the crisis support service &lt;a href="https://www.lifeline.org.au/"&gt;Lifeline&lt;/a&gt; is 13 11 14. Other international helplines can be found at &lt;a href="http://www.befrienders.org/"&gt;befrienders.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/law/2024/mar/15/diogo-santos-coelho-pleads-uk-block-us-extradition-cybercrime-raidforums"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 12:09:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Maybe everybody feels socially awkward’: the standups turning being autistic into a comedy superpower</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2024/mar/16/autism-comedy-superpower-fern-brady-pierre-novellie-joe-wells-charlie-george</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From Fern Brady to Hannah Gadsby, a host of comedians have discovered that they are autistic. What is it about standup that lends itself so well to neurodivergent people?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2020, Pierre Novellie was previewing an early version of&amp;nbsp; his standup show Why Can’t I&amp;nbsp;Just Enjoy Things? – things such as holidays and trips to the cinema (due to the “all the chewing and rustling packets”) – when he was interrupted by an audience member’s polite heckle. “He said: ‘You&amp;nbsp;sound like me,’” recalls Novellie. The&amp;nbsp;comedian asked what that meant. “He said: ‘I have Asperger’s – I think you have Asperger’s.’”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day, Novellie began seriously looking into the prospect that he was autistic (the term Asperger’s is no longer commonly used, partly because of its namesake’s Nazi affiliations, but&amp;nbsp;some autistic people still refer to it). He began taking multiple online tests, alternating between answering completely truthfully and “in the most normal, sociable way” he could, yet both approaches put him firmly above the threshold for autism. In 2022, he finally received a formal diagnosis – by&amp;nbsp;which point he’d realised that the title of Why Can’t I Just Enjoy Things? wasn’t rhetorical. “It turned out there was an answer: these were inherently autistic routines,” says Novellie (in&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;case of rustling packets, sound sensitivity is common in autistic people). “So that became the ending of&amp;nbsp;the show.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2024/mar/16/autism-comedy-superpower-fern-brady-pierre-novellie-joe-wells-charlie-george"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 14:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘A talented, goofy kid’: family of Ryan Gainer, autistic teen killed by police, speak out</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/mar/21/ryan-gainer-autistic-teen-police-killing-california</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shooting of 15-year-old ‘beautiful soul’ in California revives scrutiny on law enforcement abuse of youth with disabilities&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Ryan Gainer was diagnosed with autism as a toddler, he was nonverbal, and his family all learned sign language to communicate with him. But after the southern California boy learned how to speak at around age four, he was a “ball of energy” who never stopped talking, his older sister Rachel said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He loved saying “hi” to neighbors and strangers alike, and as a young teen was known as the student who greeted everyone with a “good morning” and a smile.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/mar/21/ryan-gainer-autistic-teen-police-killing-california"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 23:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Questioning the diagnosis of autism denies the difficulties people like me live with | Anthony Castle</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2024/mar/25/autism-diagnosis-ndis</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being autistic doesn’t explain everything about me – but it helps make sense of my experiences&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;morning and afternoon news emails&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a man alongside me. He is well put-together, hand outstretched, deep voice. I stand in a room filled with competent people who look the part. I am there in my role, to get a story, but I have not been sleeping or eating. I feel as if I can’t breathe. The man is questioning me: Who are you? What do you do? I can’t answer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am covering a fundraising event as a journalist. I know why the man is questioning me – I have lost my name tag – but in this moment I am not able to answer. It has been one week since I was diagnosed with autism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed"&gt;Sign up for Guardian Australia’s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2024/mar/25/autism-diagnosis-ndis"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 01:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S6 Ep 7: Cat Burns, singer</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/audio/2024/mar/26/s6-ep-7-cat-burns-singer</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Platinum-selling singer songwriter Cat Burns cosies up with Grace for a warm plate of nosh and some deep chats. The biggest-selling British female artist of 2022, who won three Brit award nominations after her single Go went viral on TikTok, reveals how she went from shy schoolgirl to stadium gigs in just a few years. While Covid put an end to busking on the South Bank, it opened up another portal on social channels that sent Cat’s star on its rapid ascent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently diagnosed as autistic, Cat explains how her relationship with food thrives on predictability and consistency. Yet with a small recipe suggestion from her girlfriend, she had a lightbulb moment – opening up new possibilities. Cat says she doesn’t do small talk, which is more than OK; her big talk is just beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;New episodes of Comfort Eating with Grace Dent will be released every Tuesday&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/audio/2024/mar/26/s6-ep-7-cat-burns-singer"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 05:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Everybody has a breaking point’: how the climate crisis affects our brains</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2024/mar/27/everybody-has-a-breaking-point-how-the-climate-crisis-affects-our-brains</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are growing rates of anxiety, depression, ADHD, PTSD, Alzheimer’s and motor neurone disease related to rising temperatures and other extreme environmental changes?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In late October 2012, a category 3 hurricane howled into New York City with a force that would etch &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2022/oct/29/new-york-hurricane-sandy-climate-protest"&gt;its name into the annals of history&lt;/a&gt;. Superstorm Sandy transformed the city, inflicting more than $60bn in damage, killing dozens, and &lt;a href="https://www.nyc.gov/html/sirr/downloads/pdf/final_report/Ch_1_SandyImpacts_FINAL_singles.pdf"&gt;forcing&lt;/a&gt; 6,500 patients to be evacuated from hospitals and nursing homes. Yet in the case of one cognitive neuroscientist, the storm presented, darkly, an opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yoko Nomura had found herself at the centre of a natural experiment. Prior to the hurricane’s unexpected visit, Nomura – who teaches in the psychology department at Queens College, CUNY, as well as in the psychiatry department of the Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai – had meticulously assembled a research cohort of hundreds of expectant New York mothers. Her investigation, the &lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ije/article/46/5/1388/2907773"&gt;Stress in Pregnancy study&lt;/a&gt;, had aimed since 2009 to explore the potential imprint of prenatal stress on the unborn. Drawing on the evolving field of epigenetics, Nomura had sought to understand the ways in which environmental stressors could spur changes in gene expression, the likes of which were already known to influence the risk of specific childhood neurobehavioural outcomes such as autism, schizophrenia and &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2024/feb/21/adhd-may-have-been-an-evolutionary-advantage-research-suggests"&gt;attention deficit hyperactivity disorder&lt;/a&gt; (ADHD).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2024/mar/27/everybody-has-a-breaking-point-how-the-climate-crisis-affects-our-brains"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 05:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Female Character by Fern Brady review – moving account of undiagnosed autism</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2024/mar/29/strong-female-character-by-fern-brady-review-moving-account-of-undiagnosed-autism</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Scottish comedian narrates her traumatic experience of being ‘wired differently’ and why autism is so frequently missed in women&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the Scottish comedian Fern Brady phoned her father to say she had been diagnosed with autism, he was on his daily commute back from London. He said, “Oh right”, and began complaining about the traffic. Brady replied: “Well, they say autism can be inherited from one parent, so I guess that’s answered the question of which one.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Strong Female Character, written and narrated by Brady, and winner of the inaugural Nero award for nonfiction, documents the&amp;nbsp;turmoil of growing up with undiagnosed autism, during which she excelled academically but struggled with sensory overload and had violent outbursts that baffled her family, teachers and peers. After she began self-harming, her parents sent her to an adolescent psychiatric unit where she was a day patient. She was diagnosed with obsessive compulsive disorder, though she knew that wasn’t the whole story. It took until she was 34 to get an autism diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2024/mar/29/strong-female-character-by-fern-brady-review-moving-account-of-undiagnosed-autism"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 12:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK’s black children ‘face cultural barriers’ in accessing help for autism and ADHD</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2024/mar/31/uk-black-children-cultural-barriers-accessing-help-autism-adhd</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Campaigner Marsha Martin says ‘there is a lot of stigma within black community’ that prevents issues from being discussed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cultural barriers are preventing black children who are autistic or have attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) from accessing the help they need, the founder of a UK campaign for better support has said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of children with special educational needs (Send) routinely &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2024/feb/18/hundreds-of-children-with-special-needs-wait-a-year-for-support-in-england"&gt;wait&lt;/a&gt; for more than a year to get help as local authorities across England struggle to meet unprecedented need in a dire financial climate.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2024/mar/31/uk-black-children-cultural-barriers-accessing-help-autism-adhd"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 08:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The sudden rise of AuDHD: what is behind the rocketing rates of this life-changing diagnosis?</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2024/apr/04/audhd-what-is-behind-rocketing-rates-life-changing-diagnosis</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just over a decade ago, autism and ADHD were thought to be mutually exclusive. But in recent years, all that has changed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He had beaten more than 19,000&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;applicants for a place at medical school, yet Khurram Sadiq was now bunking off his hospital shifts. The 19-year-old felt inexplicably anxious around strangers on the wards and was hiding from his own&amp;nbsp;patients.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;During lectures he couldn’t focus on what he was being taught. He deemed himself “a goof, a dunce” in contrast to his peers. Sadiq couldn’t motivate himself to revise for his exams and instead found himself panic reading textbooks in the final days. He passed his undergraduate pre-medical exams by the skin of his teeth.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That was 30 years ago. In the decades since, Dr Sadiq has qualified as a consultant psychiatrist, been diagnosed with both autism and attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD),&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;specialised in autism and ADHD psychiatry and met hundreds of patients with struggles similar to his. He is now trying to spread what was once an unbelievable message: that both autism and ADHD can coexist in the same person&amp;nbsp;simultaneously.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Just over a decade ago, the two conditions were considered to be mutually exclusive, with the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, often referred to as “psychiatry’s bible”, stating that the diagnosis of one &lt;a href="https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__www.spectrumnews.org_news_new-2Drules-2Dallow-2Djoint-2Ddiagnosis-2Dof-2Dautism-2Dattention-2Ddeficit_&amp;amp;amp;d=DwMFaQ&amp;amp;amp;c=euGZstcaTDllvimEN8b7jXrwqOf-v5A_CdpgnVfiiMM&amp;amp;amp;r=WkcRK3Crq-fGerXGdpVAxhQa54b7o8GzP26Di4ZpJJo&amp;amp;amp;m=WBMiMfilEOObsC96W7gW8PJ296Ba5mN66TYhc3Oso7RLLZzLWDcWXuAQODmgeOdG&amp;amp;amp;s=HQkfxBMBQixv0NPtxazwjzfV3TZBizDZC2ZHhWtsJlc&amp;amp;amp;e="&gt;precluded the existence&lt;/a&gt; of the other.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;This wasn’t revised until 2013. “It led to a fork in the road,” says Dr Jessica Eccles, spokesperson for the Royal College of Psychiatrists. “Not only for clinical practice, but also for research and public understanding of these conditions.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now some specialists believe that the coexistence of both conditions is not just possible, but frequent. &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3441928/"&gt;One study&lt;/a&gt; by researchers at Duke University found that up to half of people diagnosed as autistic also exhibit ADHD symptoms, and that characteristics of autism are present in two-thirds of people with ADHD. “My clinical experience suggests it’s more than three-quarters in both directions,” adds Dr Eccles.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Online, the idea that autism and ADHD can coexist is so widely accepted that it has spawned its own label – “AuDHD” – and a groundswell of people who say they recognise its oxymoronic nature, perpetual internal war and rollercoaster of needs. There are tens of thousands of people in AuDHD self-help forums, and millions more watching AuDHD&amp;nbsp;videos.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some of those videos come from Samantha Stein, a British YouTuber. “The fact that you can have both [autism and ADHD] at the same time is kind of paradoxical in nature,” she admits. “You think: ‘How can you be extremely rigid and need routines and structure, but also be completely incapable&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;maintaining a routine and structure?’”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The 38-year-old started making videos on autism after her diagnosis in 2019, then began covering AuDHD after learning that she also had ADHD. “I realised that autistic adults – especially those who are diagnosed late in life – more often than not seem to have ADHD as well,” says Stein. Her first video on the subject, “&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/pMx1DnSn-eg?si=iAHmDB7SkXXe8Kqf"&gt;5 signs you have ADHD and autism&lt;/a&gt;”, has now been viewed more than 2m times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some critics like to describe ADHD – and more recently autism – as a “fashionable” diagnosis, a misinformed excuse for life’s struggles. It’s almost inevitable that the new AuDHD label will cause a similar backlash. To see just how misguided this is, we must first understand both autism and ADHD. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Both are lifelong neurodevelopmental conditions that affect how people think, perceive the world and interact with others, according to &lt;a href="https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__embracingcomplexity.org.uk_news_special-2Dinterest-2Dresearch-2Dgroup&amp;amp;amp;d=DwMFaQ&amp;amp;amp;c=euGZstcaTDllvimEN8b7jXrwqOf-v5A_CdpgnVfiiMM&amp;amp;amp;r=WkcRK3Crq-fGerXGdpVAxhQa54b7o8GzP26Di4ZpJJo&amp;amp;amp;m=WBMiMfilEOObsC96W7gW8PJ296Ba5mN66TYhc3Oso7RLLZzLWDcWXuAQODmgeOdG&amp;amp;amp;s=8gEk4PKxS5wTd5SBZNOLy2v6utyjb5gfNmnH7S4DsYA&amp;amp;amp;e="&gt;Embracing Complexity&lt;/a&gt;, an umbrella group of organisations that research neurodiversity.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2024/apr/04/audhd-what-is-behind-rocketing-rates-life-changing-diagnosis"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 04:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NHS faces ‘avalanche’ of demand for autism and ADHD services, thinktank warns</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/apr/04/nhs-faces-avalanche-of-demand-for-autism-and-adhd-services-thinktank-warns</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nuffield Trust says system for treatment is ‘obsolete’ as number of patients in England awaiting assessment hits record high&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NHS is experiencing an “avalanche of need” over autism and attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD), but the system in place to cope with surging demand for assessments and treatments is “obsolete”, a health thinktank has warned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There must be a “radical rethink” of how people with the conditions are cared for in England if the health service is to meet the rapidly expanding need for services, according to the Nuffield Trust.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/apr/04/nhs-faces-avalanche-of-demand-for-autism-and-adhd-services-thinktank-warns"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 07:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Met investigates 'stem-cell autism cure' claim</title>
      <link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-london-68759263</link>
      <description>The local council says it is aware of concerns over "experimental procedures" on autistic children.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 12:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Sensory Needs During the Holidays</title>
      <link>https://www.autismbc.ca/blog/sensory-friendly-holidays/</link>
      <description>This time of year is filled with an abundance of sensory stimuli unique to the holidays. The lights are brighter, the scents are richer, the food is special, and every day it seems like there is something else to do. For those of us with sensory processing challenges, it can easily become too much. Here are some tips from both a parent’s and autistic adult’s perspective to make this holiday season a little more sensory-friendly.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holidays</title>
      <link>https://www.autismspeaks.org/holidays</link>
      <description>Holidays can be both the best of times and the worst of times for autistic individuals and their families. Changes in routine, increased social demands, crowds and gatherings, new activities, sensory overloaded events, unfamiliar foods and other out-of-the-ordinary experiences can all present challenges.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>

