<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Autism News</title>
    <link>https://rcastonguay.github.io/autismfeeds/index.xml</link>
    <description>An RSS feed filtered by autism keywords.</description>
    <atom:link href="https://rcastonguay.github.io/autismfeeds/index.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 03:19:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Pierre Novellie: ‘A heckler diagnosed my Asperger’s so fair play to him’</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2023/may/22/pierre-novellie-comedy-q-and-a-heckler-diagnosed-my-aspergers</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The comedian on his worst gig, preshow rituals and receiving an ASD diagnosis after an audience intervention&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did you start doing standup?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I always wondered if I was funny. Or rather if my private sense of humour, that I shared with very few people, would work on the public. That and being obsessed with comedy meant I was always going to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who inspired you when you were starting out?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;I was inspired as a teenager by watching club comics perform on the various compilation shows of early 00s television (Live at the Store, Comedy Blue, etc) but also by people like Eddie Izzard and Dave Chappelle. When I read Frank Skinner’s descriptions of standup as the freest you can be, I was sold. I had to try it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2023/may/22/pierre-novellie-comedy-q-and-a-heckler-diagnosed-my-aspergers"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 08:42:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books with neurodivergent characters mark new chapter for publishers</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2023/jun/14/books-with-neurodivergent-characters-mark-new-chapter-for-publishers</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Children’s books featuring protagonists who are autistic or have ADHD are going to the highest bidder&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Children’s books that feature neurodiverse main characters are the latest publishing trend, experts have said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Publishers, which were previously reluctant to approach the subject, are increasingly seeking out realistic and explicitly neurodiverse protagonists, often by authors who are themselves neurodivergent.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2023/jun/14/books-with-neurodivergent-characters-mark-new-chapter-for-publishers"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 15:48:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The mother of neurodiversity: how Judy Singer changed the world</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/jul/05/the-mother-of-neurodiversity-how-judy-singer-changed-the-world</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1997 she transformed the way we think about human difference – and provided a name for a burgeoning movement&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Judy Singer is several thousand miles from her Australian home, on a two-week trip around the UK, which includes an onstage interview at Cambridge University and her receipt of an honorary fellowship from Birkbeck, University of London. Soon after we meet, she will do a round of sightseeing, then travel to meet relatives in Hungary. Her itinerary sounds very taxing, but her tiredness is combined with the pleasure of being belatedly honoured for her trailblazing work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We meet in a central London cafe where, for nearly three hours, she guides me through a life story that takes in the aftermath of the Holocaust, life in communist eastern Europe, her family’s migration to Australia, and a life that has mixed academia and activism with plenty of struggle and hardship. But what we talk about the most is neurodiversity, the concept she quietly introduced to the world in 1997.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/jul/05/the-mother-of-neurodiversity-how-judy-singer-changed-the-world"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 09:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Playing the drums is therapy in action | James Wood</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/jul/09/hitting-drums-therapy-drumming-teenagers-autism</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Research shows that drumming has benefits for teenagers with autism in terms of the brain, the body and attention levels&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s amazing that the young &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/theguardian/2010/sep/08/archive-keith-moon-found-dead" title=""&gt;Keith Moon&lt;/a&gt; got any education at all. At his Wembley school he was hyperactive, easily distracted, addicted to practical jokes – the sort of boy who, in the 1950s and 60s, got quickly spat out of the educational system. A friend later told Moon’s biographer: “You never felt: ‘One day he is going to be famous.’ You felt more likely that he was going to end up in prison.” Nowadays he’d be diagnosed with ADHD, drugged into discipline and eased into some of the gentler GCSEs. Fortunately for everyone else, he discovered drumming and joined &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/who" title=""&gt;the Who&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Playing the drums makes me think of Karl Kraus’s famous crack about psychoanalysis: it’s the mental illness for which it considers itself the therapy. Is drumming the symptom of lawless restlessness, showing off, a desire to make a very loud noise – or the cure for it? Recent research provides the answer: it’s the cure. A 2018 survey by Dr Ruth Lowry at the University of Essex suggested that drumming improved the motor skills and social health of kids with behavioural and emotional challenges. A new survey, led by the same researcher and organised by the &lt;a href="https://clemburkedrummingproject.org/" title=""&gt;Clem Burke Drumming Project&lt;/a&gt; (Burke is the terrific &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2023/jun/25/blondie-at-glastonbury-review-debbie-harry" title=""&gt;drummer for Blondie&lt;/a&gt;) goes further. The new study divided 36 teenagers with varieties of autism into two groups, one receiving drumming lessons for two months and one going without. The teenagers who played the drums showed a marked decrease in hyperactivity and inattention.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/jul/09/hitting-drums-therapy-drumming-teenagers-autism"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 07:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We were inundated’: creating pioneering homes for autistic young adults</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/10/we-were-inundated-creating-pioneering-homes-for-autistic-young-adults</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the success of Linden Farm, the Simon Trust helps families create specialised local residences for their adult children with highly complex needs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parents across the UK are forming partnerships with local councils to build pioneering supported-living homes for their autistic children with high needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With growing numbers of parents increasingly unable to find suitable, safe and secure residential accommodation for their young adult children – and cash-strapped councils having to pay exorbitant costs when already expensive placements break down – the two are coming together to forge a solution.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/10/we-were-inundated-creating-pioneering-homes-for-autistic-young-adults"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 05:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jason Arday: he learned to talk at 11 and read at 18 – then became Cambridge's youngest Black professor</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/11/jason-arday-cambridge-university-youngest-black-professor</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Diagnosed with autism as a child, Arday found his voice through speech therapy and his mother’s unflagging support. Now he is using it with the same tenacity that saw him run 30 marathons in 35 days&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jason Arday believes in destiny. The University of Cambridge’s youngest Black professor, he joined its faculty of education in March 2023, at 37. Before then, he had been a professor at Glasgow and Durham universities; published three books of academic work, mainly focusing on race and education; and, most importantly to him, raised more than £5m by doing charity work. All of this he has squeezed into a time period where he was learning to navigate the world with neurodivergence; Arday didn’t speak until he was 11 and couldn’t read or write until the age of 18.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s an unlikely story, he concedes, one that has made headlines and changed his life irrevocably. But he believes he was always going to do something great. “I knew I was destined to do something,” he says with a smile. “But I didn’t know it’d be this, admittedly.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/11/jason-arday-cambridge-university-youngest-black-professor"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 09:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK children waiting 16 months on average for ADHD and autism screening – study</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/17/uk-children-waiting-16-months-on-average-for-adhd-and-autism-screening-study</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Exclusive: Belfast has worst data, with typical wait of five years to be seen, against Nice guidance of 13-week maximum&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Children with suspected ADHD and autism are waiting as long as seven years for treatment on the NHS, as the health service struggles to manage a surge in demand during a crisis in child mental health.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experts said “inhumane” waits are putting a generation of neurodiverse children at risk of mental illness as they are “pushed to the back of a very long queue” for children and adolescent mental health services (Camhs).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/17/uk-children-waiting-16-months-on-average-for-adhd-and-autism-screening-study"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 05:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autism could be seen as part of personality for some diagnosed, experts say</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/31/autism-could-be-seen-as-part-of-personality-for-some-diagnosed-experts-say</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Autism without intellectual disabilities could be reframed as human ‘variability’ rather than medical condition, says sociologist&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/31/adults-finally-diagnosed-autism-adhd"&gt;‘I recognised myself for the first time’: the adults finally diagnosed as autistic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;With a seven-fold rise in diagnoses of autism in the past 20 years in the UK, studies showing one in 36 children could be on the spectrum and waiting lists for help and support at record highs, awareness of neurodiversity has never been so high.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, key voices are arguing that some autistic people could no longer be considered as having a disability at all. Instead, their autism could be regarded as part of their personality.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/31/autism-could-be-seen-as-part-of-personality-for-some-diagnosed-experts-say"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 17:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘I recognised myself for the first time’: the adults finally diagnosed as autistic</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/31/adults-finally-diagnosed-autism-adhd</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Antoinette Monks was diagnosed with autism and ADHD at 71, while Debra Brisch got her diagnosis at 68. Both say it was life-changing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/31/autism-could-be-seen-as-part-of-personality-for-some-diagnosed-experts-say"&gt;Autism could be seen as part of personality for some diagnosed, experts say&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Antoinette Monks was diagnosed with autism and probable inattentive ADHD last year, at 71 years old.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I have always known that I was different and always let everyone down but I didn’t know why,” she said. “That ‘not knowing why’ has haunted me throughout my life but it seemed impossible that I would ever find out why I behaved as I did.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/jul/31/adults-finally-diagnosed-autism-adhd"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 17:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>School phone ban would hit autistic children the hardest | Letter</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/aug/03/school-phone-ban-would-hit-autistic-children-the-hardest</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Barring smartphones from schools – as proposed by the UN – could leave autistic pupils feeling lost and overwhelmed, warns &lt;strong&gt;Carrie Myshkin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I didn’t grow up with a smartphone at school. I’m 36. I had to make do with portable CD players and books. Nowadays, my phone is a vital part of my life. As an autistic person, it helps me play music and meditate, and generally shut out some of the overwhelmingness of the outside world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That could have helped me so much, had it been available to me when I was at school. I can read and listen to books on my phone, both of which would, again, have been massively helpful to me at school.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/aug/03/school-phone-ban-would-hit-autistic-children-the-hardest"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 17:20:26 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smartphones aren’t the answer for all autistic people | Letters</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/aug/06/smartphones-arent-the-answer-for-all-autistic-people</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elaine Bennett&lt;/strong&gt; believes the increasing use of technology is only serving to further isolate some people in a neurotypical world&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I disagree with your correspondent (&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/aug/03/school-phone-ban-would-hit-autistic-children-the-hardest" title=""&gt;Letters, 3 August&lt;/a&gt;) that a ban on mobile phones in schools will impact pupils with autistic spectrum disorder (ASD) negatively. People with ASD are already at risk of being pushed away from contact with other people and offered technology as an answer to every need.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have ASD and I’m increasingly finding that the answers to any difficulties I have are all technological ones, often involving a smartphone that I don’t have. Having ASD does not equate to preferring to not speak to other humans. I feel that technology is being used as another way to silo people out of a neurotypical world.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/aug/06/smartphones-arent-the-answer-for-all-autistic-people"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 15:19:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wired differently: how neurodiversity adds new skillsets to the workplace</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2023/aug/25/wired-differently-how-neurodiversity-adds-new-skillsets-to-the-workplace</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the arts to the law, employers are seeing conditions such as autism and ADHD can have more benefits than drawbacks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For most of his years as an actor and theatre-maker, Adam Welsh did not know he had attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder. Neither did his agent, nor anyone he worked with. But since being diagnosed at the age of 34, he has realised the impact ADHD had on his career.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I just found myself repeatedly in situations where employers wanted to let me go because of my behaviour,” he says.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2023/aug/25/wired-differently-how-neurodiversity-adds-new-skillsets-to-the-workplace"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 07:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>National Disability Insurance Agency accused of ‘failing’ young children with autism</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/aug/29/national-disability-insurance-agency-accused-of-failing-young-children-with-autism</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Committee hears every family Austism Partnerships Australia worked with who challenged their NDIS funding rejection was eventually approved for intensive support&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2023/aug/29/australia-news-live-anthony-albanese-indigenous-voice-to-parliament-perth-china-yang-henjun-climate-cost-of-living-reserve-bank"&gt;Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2022/oct/29/email-newsletters-guardian-australia-best-daily-news-emails-newsletter-free-sign-up-inbox-subscribe-headlines?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;morning and afternoon news emails&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The National Disability Insurance Agency is failing young children severely affected by autism by rejecting their claims for intensive support funding only to do an about-face after families have spent months in a lengthy, expensive tribunal process, a parliamentary committee has heard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autism Partnerships Australia (APA) told the joint standing committee on the National Disability Insurance Scheme (NDIS) the agency was “getting the planning decisions wrong” for 100% of the autistic children in its early intensive services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2022/oct/29/email-newsletters-guardian-australia-best-daily-news-emails-newsletter-free-sign-up-inbox-subscribe-headlines?CMP=copyembed"&gt;Sign up for Guardian Australia’s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/aug/29/national-disability-insurance-agency-accused-of-failing-young-children-with-autism"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 06:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No sleep, meltdowns and Billie Eilish: my first music festival as an autistic person</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2023/aug/29/billie-eilish-reading-festival-as-an-autistic-person</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I took the plunge at this year’s Reading festival, where sensory overload and mobility issues posed problems. Could I make it to the headline acts? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since my teenage years, I’ve always wanted to attend a music festival. But as an autistic person, the thought of being crammed into a loud, rowdy crowd of tens of thousands of people has always scared me. For years I avoided them. Instead, I would watch my friends enjoy themselves at big festivals from the sidelines of social media platforms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, after experiencing a bad breakup in January and adopting a mindset of trying new things, I decided to take the plunge and go to this year’s Reading festival with my friend. This decision to leave my comfort zone was made easier by a quick Google search revealing that Reading festival offers a range of disabled access services.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2023/aug/29/billie-eilish-reading-festival-as-an-autistic-person"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 14:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Children are holding a mirror up to us’: why are England’s kids refusing to go to school?</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2023/sep/02/children-are-holding-a-mirror-up-to-us-why-are-britains-kids-refusing-to-go-to-school</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For many, lockdown was a relief. Some never went back at all. As a new academic year begins, more children than ever are worried about returning. What’s being done to get them into the classroom – and is that always the best idea?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Millie was seven years old when she started struggling with going to school. Her teachers weren’t too worried initially, her mother, Sarah, says: she was managing fine academically. But Millie, who is autistic and has a sensory processing disorder, seemed to find the busy classroom overwhelming. The following year, she began seriously to resist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It would start the night before,” says Sarah, a children’s nurse. “She couldn’t sleep, couldn’t eat her dinner, then in the morning she’d be absolutely flat out – it was taking an hour to get her out of bed. I would have to dress her, she’d be like a rag doll. And all the time they kept saying, ‘Just get her in, she’s fine once she’s in.’ It got to the point where I was physically unable to carry her, she’d be lying on the floor kicking and screaming.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2023/sep/02/children-are-holding-a-mirror-up-to-us-why-are-britains-kids-refusing-to-go-to-school"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 08:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Play with cast of disabled and autistic actors to open at London’s Royal Court</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2023/sep/22/play-with-cast-of-disabled-and-autistic-actors-to-open-at-londons-royal-court</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imposter 22 will run for three weeks at renowned Sloane Square theatre and comes after series of workshops&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A play performed by a professional cast of learning disabled and autistic actors is to open at one of London’s leading theatres this weekend in a significant landmark for the arts sector.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imposter 22, a darkly comic whodunnit, will run for three weeks on the main stage of the Royal Court in Sloane Square. The play, by Molly Davies, has been five years in the making.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2023/sep/22/play-with-cast-of-disabled-and-autistic-actors-to-open-at-londons-royal-court"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 05:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making room for neurodiversity in law: Why law firms would benefit from following a more flexible hiring process.</title>
      <link>https://nationalmagazine.ca/en-ca/articles/the-practice/workplace/2023/making-room-for-neurodiversity-in-in-law</link>
      <description>Simon Margolis knew he wanted to be a lawyer. He enjoys writing, tackling conceptual problems, and diving into minutia. But psychologists told his parents he should focus on computer science instead – because Margolis is autistic. “People were saying I was bad with social skills, so ‘he should work with computers,’ but that’s not how it works,” says Margolis, a knowledge management lawyer at BLG. “We need to have more dialogue with neurodiverse people who are adults.” The University of Victoria Faculty of Law hopes to start the conversation about supporting neurodivergent people in the legal profession. This fall, the Access to Justice Centre for Excellence (ACE) launched the Canada Neurodiversity in Law project, an advocacy program.”</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>

