<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Autism News</title>
    <link>https://rcastonguay.github.io/autismfeeds/index.xml</link>
    <description>An RSS feed filtered by autism keywords.</description>
    <atom:link href="https://rcastonguay.github.io/autismfeeds/index.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 01:18:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Wired differently: how neurodiversity adds new skillsets to the workplace</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2023/aug/25/wired-differently-how-neurodiversity-adds-new-skillsets-to-the-workplace</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the arts to the law, employers are seeing conditions such as autism and ADHD can have more benefits than drawbacks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For most of his years as an actor and theatre-maker, Adam Welsh did not know he had attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder. Neither did his agent, nor anyone he worked with. But since being diagnosed at the age of 34, he has realised the impact ADHD had on his career.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I just found myself repeatedly in situations where employers wanted to let me go because of my behaviour,” he says.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2023/aug/25/wired-differently-how-neurodiversity-adds-new-skillsets-to-the-workplace"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 07:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>National Disability Insurance Agency accused of ‘failing’ young children with autism</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/aug/29/national-disability-insurance-agency-accused-of-failing-young-children-with-autism</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Committee hears every family Austism Partnerships Australia worked with who challenged their NDIS funding rejection was eventually approved for intensive support&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2023/aug/29/australia-news-live-anthony-albanese-indigenous-voice-to-parliament-perth-china-yang-henjun-climate-cost-of-living-reserve-bank"&gt;Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2022/oct/29/email-newsletters-guardian-australia-best-daily-news-emails-newsletter-free-sign-up-inbox-subscribe-headlines?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;morning and afternoon news emails&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The National Disability Insurance Agency is failing young children severely affected by autism by rejecting their claims for intensive support funding only to do an about-face after families have spent months in a lengthy, expensive tribunal process, a parliamentary committee has heard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autism Partnerships Australia (APA) told the joint standing committee on the National Disability Insurance Scheme (NDIS) the agency was “getting the planning decisions wrong” for 100% of the autistic children in its early intensive services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2022/oct/29/email-newsletters-guardian-australia-best-daily-news-emails-newsletter-free-sign-up-inbox-subscribe-headlines?CMP=copyembed"&gt;Sign up for Guardian Australia’s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/aug/29/national-disability-insurance-agency-accused-of-failing-young-children-with-autism"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 06:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No sleep, meltdowns and Billie Eilish: my first music festival as an autistic person</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2023/aug/29/billie-eilish-reading-festival-as-an-autistic-person</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I took the plunge at this year’s Reading festival, where sensory overload and mobility issues posed problems. Could I make it to the headline acts? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since my teenage years, I’ve always wanted to attend a music festival. But as an autistic person, the thought of being crammed into a loud, rowdy crowd of tens of thousands of people has always scared me. For years I avoided them. Instead, I would watch my friends enjoy themselves at big festivals from the sidelines of social media platforms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, after experiencing a bad breakup in January and adopting a mindset of trying new things, I decided to take the plunge and go to this year’s Reading festival with my friend. This decision to leave my comfort zone was made easier by a quick Google search revealing that Reading festival offers a range of disabled access services.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2023/aug/29/billie-eilish-reading-festival-as-an-autistic-person"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 14:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Children are holding a mirror up to us’: why are England’s kids refusing to go to school?</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2023/sep/02/children-are-holding-a-mirror-up-to-us-why-are-britains-kids-refusing-to-go-to-school</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For many, lockdown was a relief. Some never went back at all. As a new academic year begins, more children than ever are worried about returning. What’s being done to get them into the classroom – and is that always the best idea?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Millie was seven years old when she started struggling with going to school. Her teachers weren’t too worried initially, her mother, Sarah, says: she was managing fine academically. But Millie, who is autistic and has a sensory processing disorder, seemed to find the busy classroom overwhelming. The following year, she began seriously to resist.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It would start the night before,” says Sarah, a children’s nurse. “She couldn’t sleep, couldn’t eat her dinner, then in the morning she’d be absolutely flat out – it was taking an hour to get her out of bed. I would have to dress her, she’d be like a rag doll. And all the time they kept saying, ‘Just get her in, she’s fine once she’s in.’ It got to the point where I was physically unable to carry her, she’d be lying on the floor kicking and screaming.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2023/sep/02/children-are-holding-a-mirror-up-to-us-why-are-britains-kids-refusing-to-go-to-school"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 08:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Play with cast of disabled and autistic actors to open at London’s Royal Court</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2023/sep/22/play-with-cast-of-disabled-and-autistic-actors-to-open-at-londons-royal-court</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imposter 22 will run for three weeks at renowned Sloane Square theatre and comes after series of workshops&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A play performed by a professional cast of learning disabled and autistic actors is to open at one of London’s leading theatres this weekend in a significant landmark for the arts sector.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imposter 22, a darkly comic whodunnit, will run for three weeks on the main stage of the Royal Court in Sloane Square. The play, by Molly Davies, has been five years in the making.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2023/sep/22/play-with-cast-of-disabled-and-autistic-actors-to-open-at-londons-royal-court"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 05:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adult ADHD and autism assessment requests blocked by NHS screening system</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/oct/29/adult-adhd-autism-assessment-nhs-screening-system-yorkshire-pilot</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yorkshire pilot scheme to combat rise in waiting times has not resulted in a single appraisal&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A new screening system for adults wanting an &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/autism" title=""&gt;autism&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/attention-deficit-hyperactivity-disorder" title=""&gt;ADHD diagnosis&lt;/a&gt; has rejected up to 85% of requests for a referral since it was launched, adding to concerns from campaigners who warn it could become a blueprint across the NHS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In March, NHS bosses in York and North Yorkshire launched a pilot of a system for adults seeking an autism or ADHD diagnosis in response to rising demand and long waiting times.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/oct/29/adult-adhd-autism-assessment-nhs-screening-system-yorkshire-pilot"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 05:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Penelope My Love review – admirably honest portrait of a mother and her autistic child</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2023/nov/13/penelope-my-love-review-admirably-honest-portrait-of-a-mother-and-her-autistic-child</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Film-maker Claire Doyon’s bio-doc charts the rich but deeply challenging experiences of being a parent to daughter Pénélope and the intense bond that changes as they both grow older&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2012, French film-maker Claire Doyon made &lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt2356424/"&gt;Pénélope&lt;/a&gt;, a 50-minute documentary, about taking her autistic daughter Pénélope to deepest Mongolia to meet a shaman. As a parent of children with autism, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/filmblog/2011/apr/04/autism-best-film-portraits"&gt;I made it a mission to watch as many films as I could&lt;/a&gt; about the condition, and this unfortunately appears to have slipped through the net and is not available anywhere, at least in the UK or US.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That elusiveness alone might suggest that Doyon’s own feelings about the film, her daughter and her quest to find ways to cope with Pénélope’s condition have changed over the years. What’s more, she has now made another film, Penelope My Love, which incorporates footage from her earlier work, forming what feels more like a revision than a mere revisiting.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2023/nov/13/penelope-my-love-review-admirably-honest-portrait-of-a-mother-and-her-autistic-child"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 07:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disability advocate hits back at ‘misleading’ claims that NDIS funding is incentivising autism diagnoses</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/nov/22/disability-advocate-hits-back-at-misleading-claims-that-ndis-funding-is-incentivising-autism-diagnoses</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chief of Children and Young People with Disability Australia says families are simply seeking help for their children, with the NDIS ‘the only place to turn’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2023/nov/22/australia-news-live-cyber-strategy-clare-oneil-protest-nsw-antisemitism-palestine-anthonoy-albanese-peter-dutton"&gt;Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;morning and afternoon news emails&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;An advocate for people with disabilities has criticised as “unhelpful” and “misleading” reports suggesting families are pursuing autism diagnoses because they see the NDIS as a financial opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The NDIS isn’t a sort of financial incentive,” said Skye Kakoschke-Moore, chief executive of Children and Young People with Disability Australia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed"&gt;Sign up for Guardian Australia’s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/nov/22/disability-advocate-hits-back-at-misleading-claims-that-ndis-funding-is-incentivising-autism-diagnoses"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cruel and irresponsible myths about the NDIS are treating autistic Australians as villains. This must stop | Clem Bastow and Ali Schnabel</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/commentisfree/2023/dec/06/autistic-australians-must-stop-being-treated-as-villains-in-cruel-and-irresponsible-myths-about-the-ndis</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Narratives about the so-called ‘epidemic’ of autism typically do not make the distinction between autistic people and diagnoses&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autistic people and those who support them know one thing to be true: wait long enough and we’ll be back in the news again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In mid-November, an internal review paper suggested that NDIS funding could be “incentivising” families to seek autism diagnoses for their children. The paper was widely reported upon in Australian media but, by the time it was &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/nov/22/disability-advocate-hits-back-at-misleading-claims-that-ndis-funding-is-incentivising-autism-diagnoses"&gt;criticised by disability advocates&lt;/a&gt;, a particularly cruel narrative about autistic people had once again reared its head. As an autistic person, and a psychologist who works to support them, we are troubled by the often irresponsible reporting regarding autism and the NDIS.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/commentisfree/2023/dec/06/autistic-australians-must-stop-being-treated-as-villains-in-cruel-and-irresponsible-myths-about-the-ndis"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The new Tory austerity will be like nothing we've seen before. Here is its human cost | Frances Ryan</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/dec/08/tory-austerity-jeremy-hunt-cuts-public-services</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jeremy Hunt’s planned cuts will mean the death of public services. The lives of Britain’s most vulnerable people are on the line&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Vicky forgets to buy food, she doesn’t eat. Autism means she often can’t manage day-to-day tasks: from cleaning the house and remembering to wash to doing the weekly shop. “I can’t cope with being outside for any real length of time,” she says. “And sometimes it can take me four days to complete one online shop.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her medication goes the same way. When Vicky doesn’t order her antidepressants, she can’t sleep. Without her painkillers for her arthritis, she struggles to move. Rising bills on top of low benefits have only added to the distress. Vicky is now £1,600 in debt to her energy company, but her disability means she can’t call them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Frances Ryan is a Guardian columnist&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article was amended on 8 December 2023 to remove a reference to libraries being a “discretionary” service; they are a statutory requirement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the UK and Ireland, &lt;a href="https://www.samaritans.org/"&gt;Samaritans&lt;/a&gt; can be contacted on freephone 116 123, or email &lt;a href="mailto:jo@samaritans.org"&gt;jo@samaritans.org&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="mailto:jo@samaritans.ie"&gt;jo@samaritans.ie&lt;/a&gt;. In the US, you can call or text the &lt;a href="https://988lifeline.org/"&gt;National Suicide Prevention Lifeline&lt;/a&gt; on 988, chat on &lt;a href="https://988lifeline.org/chat/"&gt;988lifeline.org&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.crisistextline.org/"&gt;text HOME&lt;/a&gt; to 741741 to connect with a crisis counselor. In Australia, the crisis support service &lt;a href="https://www.lifeline.org.au/"&gt;Lifeline&lt;/a&gt; is 13 11 14. Other international helplines can be found at &lt;a href="http://www.befrienders.org/"&gt;befrienders.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have an opinion on the issues raised in this article? If you would like to submit a response of up to 300 words by email to be considered for publication in our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/letters"&gt;letters&lt;/a&gt; section, please &lt;a href="mailto:mailto:guardian.letters@theguardian.com?body=Please%20include%20your%20name,%20full%20postal%20address%20and%20phone%20number%20underneath%20your%20letter.%20Letters%20are%20usually%20published%20with%20the%20author’s%20name%20and%20city/town/village.%20The%20rest%20of%20the%20information%20is%20for%20verification%20only%20and%20to%20contact%20you%20if%20your%20letter%20is%20used."&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/dec/08/tory-austerity-jeremy-hunt-cuts-public-services"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 06:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schools are failing children like mine | Letters</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/theobserver/commentisfree/2023/dec/17/schools-failing-children-like-mine-ofsted-attendance-letters</link>
      <description>The classroom is a hostile environment for my autistic son. No wonder so many pupils are skipping school&lt;p&gt;Thank you to Eva Wiseman for her compassionate article (“&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2023/dec/10/eva-wiseman-the-real-reason-why-schools-are-failing" title=""&gt;Schools today are failing – and it’s clear who needs detention&lt;/a&gt;”, Magazine). I disagree somewhat with Ofsted’s narrative about attendance. Numbers of those persistently absent have been increasing since the early 2010s and tend to happen at key-stage changes (years 1, 3, 7 and 10). This usually impacts those who are neurodiverse and have known special educational needs. Half of the pupils with persistent attendance issues experience difficulty with attendance by the age of seven. It’s convenient for Ofsted to blame parents and Covid, when actually this problem has been gradually increasing for years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have an autistic son who has had no meaningful education for over two years. Parents like me end up going to court to beg for more support or get press-ganged into “electively home educating”. There is very little Child and Adolescent Mental Health Services support for the neurodivergent.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/theobserver/commentisfree/2023/dec/17/schools-failing-children-like-mine-ofsted-attendance-letters"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 06:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extra $25bn needed to make NDIS sustainable by boosting other disability services, actuary says</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/dec/19/ndis-services-funding-government</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chair of Actuaries Institute committee says money could go towards establishing early intervention programs for those with developmental delays&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2023/dec/19/australia-news-live-more-rain-expected-in-far-north-queensland-major-bushfire-in-north-west-nsw"&gt;Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;morning and afternoon news emails&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt; free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Governments will need to invest an additional $25bn over the next five years if they are to achieve plans to rein in the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/dec/17/new-taskforce-to-crack-down-on-price-gouging-by-unscrupulous-ndis-providers"&gt;NDIS&lt;/a&gt;’s growth by lifting disability services outside the scheme to a high enough level, a leading actuary has estimated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It comes as disability organisations, particularly those advocating for the autism community, raise concerns about who will be able to access the scheme in the future, and whether those who can’t join the NDIS can still be well supported.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed"&gt;Sign up for Guardian Australia’s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/dec/19/ndis-services-funding-government"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 14:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘I have a bag on my head. Deal with it!’ Is Blindboy the perfect podcaster?</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2024/jan/12/i-have-a-bag-on-my-head-deal-with-it-is-blindboy-the-perfect-podcaster</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He wears plastic bags as an ‘autistic protest’ and makes podcasts about everything from fish fingers to the Baileys sex cult. The former Rubberbandit talks about turning his ‘weirdo’ world into millions of hits&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Childhood curiosity has genuinely never left me,” says Blindboy. “I’m curious about everything. All the time. Whatever it is, I’m always wanting to know: Why? How? What if?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This ceaseless curiosity is what has made &lt;a href="https://play.acast.com/s/blindboy" title=""&gt;The Blindboy Podcast&lt;/a&gt; such a sensation in the world of audio. Written, recorded and produced by one man in Limerick and released once a week like clockwork, it regularly pulls up to a million listeners a month from around the globe.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2024/jan/12/i-have-a-bag-on-my-head-deal-with-it-is-blindboy-the-perfect-podcaster"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 13:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We equate verbal fluency with intelligence’: why Angie Kim wrote a novel about a non-speaking autistic boy</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2024/jan/27/nonverbal-people-deserve-a-voice-angie-kim-on-why-she-wrote-a-novel-about-a-boy-with-severe-autism</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What happens when you can’t express yourself through speech? The writer&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;on her new book and her own experience of being unable to communicate&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Almost two decades ago, I went to a medical conference to learn about treatment options for my son’s ulcerative colitis. His doctor described an incident involving a non-speaking autistic teenage patient, who everyone assumed couldn’t understand anything. His parents were mystified and frustrated because his repetitive behaviours, including screaming and hitting his head against the wall, were out of control. As they were telling the doctor that his teachers were sure this was a purely behavioural issue, the boy grabbed his sister’s preschool alphabet toy and typed, &lt;em&gt;help&amp;nbsp;me it hurts&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I immediately teared up and couldn’t stop thinking about it. This is, of course, an emotional story that would affect any person. But it was acute for me, more personal, because of what I had gone through as an immigrant.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2024/jan/27/nonverbal-people-deserve-a-voice-angie-kim-on-why-she-wrote-a-novel-about-a-boy-with-severe-autism"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 11:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The week in audio: Why Do You Hate Me?; Patient 11; Theory of Everything: Not All Propaganda Is Art – review</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2024/feb/03/why-do-you-hate-me-marianna-spring-review-patient-11-alexis-quinn-theory-of-everything-not-all-propaganda-is-art-benjamen-walker</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Marianna Spring dives into her inbox to investigate cases of online hate; a young autistic woman sectioned for three years tells her shocking story. Plus, Kenneth Tynan and the CIA&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Do You Hate Me?&lt;/strong&gt; (Radio 4) | &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/m001vtl1"&gt;BBC Sounds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patient 11&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;a href="https://news.sky.com/story/patient-11-podcast-13054441"&gt;Sky News/Independent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theory of Everything: Not All Propaganda Is Art&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;a href="https://theoryofeverythingpodcast.com/2024/01/napia1/"&gt;theoryofeverythingpodcast.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The BBC’s disinformation and social media correspondent, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/sep/04/bbc-marianna-spring-violent-rhetoric-conspiracyland"&gt;Marianna Spring&lt;/a&gt;, is a woman for whom the words “sucker for punishment” were invented. Polite, cheerful, dedicated, she has spent the past few years tracking down online hooligans and conspiracy theorists in award-winning radio series such as &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/p0bpc91l"&gt;Death By Conspiracy?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/m001dpnp"&gt;Disaster Trolls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/m001mssl"&gt;Marianna &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/m001mssl"&gt;in Conspiracyland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. And now she’s back once again on Radio 4, to marshal yet more strange internet people into answering sensible questions. Or to try, at least.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2024/feb/03/why-do-you-hate-me-marianna-spring-review-patient-11-alexis-quinn-theory-of-everything-not-all-propaganda-is-art-benjamen-walker"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Sensory Needs During the Holidays</title>
      <link>https://www.autismbc.ca/blog/sensory-friendly-holidays/</link>
      <description>This time of year is filled with an abundance of sensory stimuli unique to the holidays. The lights are brighter, the scents are richer, the food is special, and every day it seems like there is something else to do. For those of us with sensory processing challenges, it can easily become too much. Here are some tips from both a parent’s and autistic adult’s perspective to make this holiday season a little more sensory-friendly.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holidays</title>
      <link>https://www.autismspeaks.org/holidays</link>
      <description>Holidays can be both the best of times and the worst of times for autistic individuals and their families. Changes in routine, increased social demands, crowds and gatherings, new activities, sensory overloaded events, unfamiliar foods and other out-of-the-ordinary experiences can all present challenges.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>

