<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Autism News</title>
    <link>https://rcastonguay.github.io/autismfeeds/index.xml</link>
    <description>An RSS feed filtered by autism keywords.</description>
    <atom:link href="https://rcastonguay.github.io/autismfeeds/index.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 01:21:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Disability advocate hits back at ‘misleading’ claims that NDIS funding is incentivising autism diagnoses</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/nov/22/disability-advocate-hits-back-at-misleading-claims-that-ndis-funding-is-incentivising-autism-diagnoses</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chief of Children and Young People with Disability Australia says families are simply seeking help for their children, with the NDIS ‘the only place to turn’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2023/nov/22/australia-news-live-cyber-strategy-clare-oneil-protest-nsw-antisemitism-palestine-anthonoy-albanese-peter-dutton"&gt;Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;morning and afternoon news emails&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;An advocate for people with disabilities has criticised as “unhelpful” and “misleading” reports suggesting families are pursuing autism diagnoses because they see the NDIS as a financial opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The NDIS isn’t a sort of financial incentive,” said Skye Kakoschke-Moore, chief executive of Children and Young People with Disability Australia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed"&gt;Sign up for Guardian Australia’s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/nov/22/disability-advocate-hits-back-at-misleading-claims-that-ndis-funding-is-incentivising-autism-diagnoses"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cruel and irresponsible myths about the NDIS are treating autistic Australians as villains. This must stop | Clem Bastow and Ali Schnabel</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/commentisfree/2023/dec/06/autistic-australians-must-stop-being-treated-as-villains-in-cruel-and-irresponsible-myths-about-the-ndis</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Narratives about the so-called ‘epidemic’ of autism typically do not make the distinction between autistic people and diagnoses&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autistic people and those who support them know one thing to be true: wait long enough and we’ll be back in the news again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In mid-November, an internal review paper suggested that NDIS funding could be “incentivising” families to seek autism diagnoses for their children. The paper was widely reported upon in Australian media but, by the time it was &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/nov/22/disability-advocate-hits-back-at-misleading-claims-that-ndis-funding-is-incentivising-autism-diagnoses"&gt;criticised by disability advocates&lt;/a&gt;, a particularly cruel narrative about autistic people had once again reared its head. As an autistic person, and a psychologist who works to support them, we are troubled by the often irresponsible reporting regarding autism and the NDIS.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/commentisfree/2023/dec/06/autistic-australians-must-stop-being-treated-as-villains-in-cruel-and-irresponsible-myths-about-the-ndis"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 00:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The new Tory austerity will be like nothing we've seen before. Here is its human cost | Frances Ryan</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/dec/08/tory-austerity-jeremy-hunt-cuts-public-services</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jeremy Hunt’s planned cuts will mean the death of public services. The lives of Britain’s most vulnerable people are on the line&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Vicky forgets to buy food, she doesn’t eat. Autism means she often can’t manage day-to-day tasks: from cleaning the house and remembering to wash to doing the weekly shop. “I can’t cope with being outside for any real length of time,” she says. “And sometimes it can take me four days to complete one online shop.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her medication goes the same way. When Vicky doesn’t order her antidepressants, she can’t sleep. Without her painkillers for her arthritis, she struggles to move. Rising bills on top of low benefits have only added to the distress. Vicky is now £1,600 in debt to her energy company, but her disability means she can’t call them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Frances Ryan is a Guardian columnist&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article was amended on 8 December 2023 to remove a reference to libraries being a “discretionary” service; they are a statutory requirement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the UK and Ireland, &lt;a href="https://www.samaritans.org/"&gt;Samaritans&lt;/a&gt; can be contacted on freephone 116 123, or email &lt;a href="mailto:jo@samaritans.org"&gt;jo@samaritans.org&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="mailto:jo@samaritans.ie"&gt;jo@samaritans.ie&lt;/a&gt;. In the US, you can call or text the &lt;a href="https://988lifeline.org/"&gt;National Suicide Prevention Lifeline&lt;/a&gt; on 988, chat on &lt;a href="https://988lifeline.org/chat/"&gt;988lifeline.org&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href="https://www.crisistextline.org/"&gt;text HOME&lt;/a&gt; to 741741 to connect with a crisis counselor. In Australia, the crisis support service &lt;a href="https://www.lifeline.org.au/"&gt;Lifeline&lt;/a&gt; is 13 11 14. Other international helplines can be found at &lt;a href="http://www.befrienders.org/"&gt;befrienders.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have an opinion on the issues raised in this article? If you would like to submit a response of up to 300 words by email to be considered for publication in our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/letters"&gt;letters&lt;/a&gt; section, please &lt;a href="mailto:mailto:guardian.letters@theguardian.com?body=Please%20include%20your%20name,%20full%20postal%20address%20and%20phone%20number%20underneath%20your%20letter.%20Letters%20are%20usually%20published%20with%20the%20author’s%20name%20and%20city/town/village.%20The%20rest%20of%20the%20information%20is%20for%20verification%20only%20and%20to%20contact%20you%20if%20your%20letter%20is%20used."&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2023/dec/08/tory-austerity-jeremy-hunt-cuts-public-services"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 06:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Schools are failing children like mine | Letters</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/theobserver/commentisfree/2023/dec/17/schools-failing-children-like-mine-ofsted-attendance-letters</link>
      <description>The classroom is a hostile environment for my autistic son. No wonder so many pupils are skipping school&lt;p&gt;Thank you to Eva Wiseman for her compassionate article (“&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2023/dec/10/eva-wiseman-the-real-reason-why-schools-are-failing" title=""&gt;Schools today are failing – and it’s clear who needs detention&lt;/a&gt;”, Magazine). I disagree somewhat with Ofsted’s narrative about attendance. Numbers of those persistently absent have been increasing since the early 2010s and tend to happen at key-stage changes (years 1, 3, 7 and 10). This usually impacts those who are neurodiverse and have known special educational needs. Half of the pupils with persistent attendance issues experience difficulty with attendance by the age of seven. It’s convenient for Ofsted to blame parents and Covid, when actually this problem has been gradually increasing for years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have an autistic son who has had no meaningful education for over two years. Parents like me end up going to court to beg for more support or get press-ganged into “electively home educating”. There is very little Child and Adolescent Mental Health Services support for the neurodivergent.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/theobserver/commentisfree/2023/dec/17/schools-failing-children-like-mine-ofsted-attendance-letters"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 06:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extra $25bn needed to make NDIS sustainable by boosting other disability services, actuary says</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/dec/19/ndis-services-funding-government</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chair of Actuaries Institute committee says money could go towards establishing early intervention programs for those with developmental delays&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2023/dec/19/australia-news-live-more-rain-expected-in-far-north-queensland-major-bushfire-in-north-west-nsw"&gt;Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;morning and afternoon news emails&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt; free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Governments will need to invest an additional $25bn over the next five years if they are to achieve plans to rein in the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/dec/17/new-taskforce-to-crack-down-on-price-gouging-by-unscrupulous-ndis-providers"&gt;NDIS&lt;/a&gt;’s growth by lifting disability services outside the scheme to a high enough level, a leading actuary has estimated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It comes as disability organisations, particularly those advocating for the autism community, raise concerns about who will be able to access the scheme in the future, and whether those who can’t join the NDIS can still be well supported.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed"&gt;Sign up for Guardian Australia’s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2023/dec/19/ndis-services-funding-government"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 14:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘I have a bag on my head. Deal with it!’ Is Blindboy the perfect podcaster?</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2024/jan/12/i-have-a-bag-on-my-head-deal-with-it-is-blindboy-the-perfect-podcaster</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He wears plastic bags as an ‘autistic protest’ and makes podcasts about everything from fish fingers to the Baileys sex cult. The former Rubberbandit talks about turning his ‘weirdo’ world into millions of hits&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Childhood curiosity has genuinely never left me,” says Blindboy. “I’m curious about everything. All the time. Whatever it is, I’m always wanting to know: Why? How? What if?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This ceaseless curiosity is what has made &lt;a href="https://play.acast.com/s/blindboy" title=""&gt;The Blindboy Podcast&lt;/a&gt; such a sensation in the world of audio. Written, recorded and produced by one man in Limerick and released once a week like clockwork, it regularly pulls up to a million listeners a month from around the globe.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2024/jan/12/i-have-a-bag-on-my-head-deal-with-it-is-blindboy-the-perfect-podcaster"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 13:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We equate verbal fluency with intelligence’: why Angie Kim wrote a novel about a non-speaking autistic boy</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2024/jan/27/nonverbal-people-deserve-a-voice-angie-kim-on-why-she-wrote-a-novel-about-a-boy-with-severe-autism</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What happens when you can’t express yourself through speech? The writer&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;on her new book and her own experience of being unable to communicate&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Almost two decades ago, I went to a medical conference to learn about treatment options for my son’s ulcerative colitis. His doctor described an incident involving a non-speaking autistic teenage patient, who everyone assumed couldn’t understand anything. His parents were mystified and frustrated because his repetitive behaviours, including screaming and hitting his head against the wall, were out of control. As they were telling the doctor that his teachers were sure this was a purely behavioural issue, the boy grabbed his sister’s preschool alphabet toy and typed, &lt;em&gt;help&amp;nbsp;me it hurts&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I immediately teared up and couldn’t stop thinking about it. This is, of course, an emotional story that would affect any person. But it was acute for me, more personal, because of what I had gone through as an immigrant.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2024/jan/27/nonverbal-people-deserve-a-voice-angie-kim-on-why-she-wrote-a-novel-about-a-boy-with-severe-autism"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 11:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The week in audio: Why Do You Hate Me?; Patient 11; Theory of Everything: Not All Propaganda Is Art – review</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2024/feb/03/why-do-you-hate-me-marianna-spring-review-patient-11-alexis-quinn-theory-of-everything-not-all-propaganda-is-art-benjamen-walker</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Marianna Spring dives into her inbox to investigate cases of online hate; a young autistic woman sectioned for three years tells her shocking story. Plus, Kenneth Tynan and the CIA&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Do You Hate Me?&lt;/strong&gt; (Radio 4) | &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/m001vtl1"&gt;BBC Sounds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patient 11&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;a href="https://news.sky.com/story/patient-11-podcast-13054441"&gt;Sky News/Independent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theory of Everything: Not All Propaganda Is Art&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;a href="https://theoryofeverythingpodcast.com/2024/01/napia1/"&gt;theoryofeverythingpodcast.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The BBC’s disinformation and social media correspondent, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/sep/04/bbc-marianna-spring-violent-rhetoric-conspiracyland"&gt;Marianna Spring&lt;/a&gt;, is a woman for whom the words “sucker for punishment” were invented. Polite, cheerful, dedicated, she has spent the past few years tracking down online hooligans and conspiracy theorists in award-winning radio series such as &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/p0bpc91l"&gt;Death By Conspiracy?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/m001dpnp"&gt;Disaster Trolls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/m001mssl"&gt;Marianna &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/sounds/play/m001mssl"&gt;in Conspiracyland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. And now she’s back once again on Radio 4, to marshal yet more strange internet people into answering sensible questions. Or to try, at least.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2024/feb/03/why-do-you-hate-me-marianna-spring-review-patient-11-alexis-quinn-theory-of-everything-not-all-propaganda-is-art-benjamen-walker"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 17:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why police are accused of radicalising an autistic teenager – podcast</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/audio/2024/feb/19/australia-police-autistic-teenager-islamic-state-fixation-operation-full-story-podcast</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When a lonely and impressionable teenager became fixated on Islamic State, police began an operation that ended up further radicalising him. At just 14, the boy was then charged with terrorism offences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Courts and justice reporter &lt;strong&gt;Nino Bucci &lt;/strong&gt;tells &lt;strong&gt;Patrick Keneally &lt;/strong&gt;how and why police targeted the vulnerable teenager, and the questions the case raises about the authorities’ role in the deradicalisation process&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;You can support the Guardian at &lt;a href="http://theguardian.com/fullstorysupport"&gt;theguardian.com/fullstorysupport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can subscribe for free to Guardian Australia’s daily &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story"&gt;news podcast Full Story&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/au/podcast/full-story/id1482061243"&gt;Apple Podcasts&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/7GJod4EyoLywB1AW6zrSHh"&gt; Spotify&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://podcasts.google.com/feed/aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cudGhlZ3VhcmRpYW4uY29tL2F1c3RyYWxpYS1uZXdzL3Nlcmllcy9mdWxsLXN0b3J5L3BvZGNhc3QueG1s?sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwjogPTcoIj_AhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAQ&amp;amp;hl=en-AU"&gt;Google Podcasts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read more:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/audio/2024/feb/19/australia-police-autistic-teenager-islamic-state-fixation-operation-full-story-podcast"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 14:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Guardian view on the special needs crisis: children don’t deserve this chaos | Editorial</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2024/feb/19/the-guardian-view-on-the-special-needs-crisis-children-dont-deserve-this-chaos</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By failing to adequately fund their own policy, ministers have created a destructive standoff between families, councils and schools&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A decade after David Cameron’s coalition government &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/teacher-network/teacher-blog/2014/feb/10/special-educational-needs-sen-reforms-five-things"&gt;overhauled provision&lt;/a&gt; for children with special educational needs and disabilities (Send) in England, it has never been clearer that the system is in crisis. A raft of measures designed to appeal to parents, by promising them greater influence over their children’s education, has resulted in a destructive standoff between families, schools and councils – because ministers failed to adequately fund their own policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead of the choices that were offered, parents of pupils who, for a range of reasons, are not thriving in mainstream classrooms, have been forced to fight for the resources that local authorities must provide to enable them to access education. &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2023/mar/26/children-put-at-risk-as-nhs-autism-assessments-are-cut-back"&gt;Long waiting times&lt;/a&gt; for NHS autism assessments, combined with &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2024/feb/18/hundreds-of-children-with-special-needs-wait-a-year-for-support-in-england"&gt;delays&lt;/a&gt; in issuing education, health and care plans (EHCPs) – the documents that set out children’s entitlements – mean that thousands of families are stuck. Even where plans have been agreed, there are many instances in which pupils do not receive the placement or support that they ought to guarantee. Families are left trapped, knowing that needs are not being met but unable to remedy what can turn into a damaging experience of exclusion from education.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2024/feb/19/the-guardian-view-on-the-special-needs-crisis-children-dont-deserve-this-chaos"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 18:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some NHS centres twice as likely to diagnose adults as autistic, study finds</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/04/some-nhs-centres-twice-as-likely-to-diagnose-adults-as-autistic-study-finds</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Landmark research suggests people have an 85% chance of positive assessment at some centres in England and 35% in others&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/04/uk-increase-autism-diagnoses-neurodiversity"&gt;What’s behind the increase in autism diagnoses?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adults awaiting an autism diagnosis face a postcode lottery in England, with some NHS centres more than twice as likely as others to give a positive assessment of the condition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Landmark research from University College London (UCL) suggests people have an 85% chance of being diagnosed as autistic in some centres compared with a 35% chance in others.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/04/some-nhs-centres-twice-as-likely-to-diagnose-adults-as-autistic-study-finds"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 14:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s behind the UK’s increase in autism diagnoses?</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/04/uk-increase-autism-diagnoses-neurodiversity</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Experts are undecided about whether there is overdiagnosis or whether more children are autistic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/04/some-nhs-centres-twice-as-likely-to-diagnose-adults-as-autistic-study-finds"&gt;Some NHS centres twice as likely to diagnose adults as autistic, study finds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autism is a condition in a state of slow flux. In &lt;a href="https://acamh.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/jcpp.13505"&gt;2021, a study&lt;/a&gt; found a 787% rise in the number of diagnoses between 1998 and 2018 in the UK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Increases in diagnoses have been a feature of autism for almost as long as it has been a recognised condition: &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4467195/#:~:text=In%20the%20mid%2D1980s%2C%20researchers,%E2%80%9Cpre%2Depidemic%E2%80%9D%20period."&gt;80 years ago&lt;/a&gt;, autism was thought to affect one in 2,500&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;children. That has gradually increased and now &lt;a href="https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lanepe/article/PIIS2666-7762(23)00045-5/fulltext"&gt;one in 36 children&lt;/a&gt; are believed to have autism spectrum disorder (ASD).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/04/uk-increase-autism-diagnoses-neurodiversity"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 14:08:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autistic pupils in England denied right to education as absenteeism surges, says charity</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/05/autistic-pupils-in-england-denied-right-to-education-as-absenteeism-surges-says-charity</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Research shows 166% rise of pupils missing one-tenth or more of school term&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/05/he-hates-failing-mother-describes-lack-of-help-for-autistic-son"&gt;‘He hates failing’: mother describes lack of help for autistic son&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autistic pupils are being denied their basic right to education, a leading charity has warned, as figures reveal the number persistently off school has increased by 166% in four years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The research shows that more than a quarter of autistic children in England – 51,000 out of about 200,000 children – are persistently absent, meaning they have missed 10% or more of the school term.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/05/autistic-pupils-in-england-denied-right-to-education-as-absenteeism-surges-says-charity"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 12:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘He hates failing’: mother describes lack of help for autistic son</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/05/he-hates-failing-mother-describes-lack-of-help-for-autistic-son</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kirsti Hadley’s son, 12, had been looking forward to a new school but became burnt out and anxious&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/05/autistic-pupils-in-england-denied-right-to-education-as-absenteeism-surges-says-charity"&gt;Autistic pupils in England denied right to education as absenteeism surges, says charity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kirsti Hadley is still reeling from how quickly her autistic son’s education has crumbled and how she cannot access help to get him back on track.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since November 2022, her 12-year-old son has only managed to spend a few hours a week at Varndean school in Brighton.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/05/he-hates-failing-mother-describes-lack-of-help-for-autistic-son"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 12:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new understanding: how research into autism is evolving</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/08/research-autism-evolving-transforming-lives-social-communication-therapy-drugs-trials</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With an emphasis on working with autistic people to design interventions, pathways are opening up through social communication therapy and drug trials&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kirsty Orton didn’t mind whether her baby was autistic or not – she just wanted her 12-month-old to enjoy being with his mummy: to notice her when she came into the room. To meet her eye when she talked to him and to be able to communicate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“All I wanted to do was be able to connect and bond with Fynn,” she said. “But when your baby looks everywhere else in the room except at you and stays in their own zone, like you’re completely unimportant to them, it’s upsetting in a way that I struggle to put into words.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/08/research-autism-evolving-transforming-lives-social-communication-therapy-drugs-trials"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 08:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Labour could rescue children from this endless series of educational crises | Letters</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2024/mar/14/how-labour-could-rescue-children-from-this-endless-series-of-educational-crises</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doreen Worthington &lt;/strong&gt;says&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;a new Education Reform Act is needed and lists what an incoming government could do&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The autism crisis (&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/mar/05/autistic-pupils-in-england-denied-right-to-education-as-absenteeism-surges-says-charity"&gt;Autistic pupils in England denied right to education as absenteeism surges, says charity, 5 March&lt;/a&gt;) is the latest in a long list of crises in English schools that the Guardian has reported on recently, including the children’s mental health crisis, the teacher recruitment and retention crisis, the headteacher retention crisis, the absenteeism crisis, the Ofsted intimidation crisis, the crisis of children not being toilet trained or knowing how to brush their teeth, the literacy crisis, the maths crisis and now the special educational needs and disabilities (Send) crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is it not time that someone (a future Labour government perhaps) started to join the dots and realise that a new Education Reform Act is needed to rescue our children from this crisis in education? They could start with a snappy election slogan – “Education, education, education” for example – and a commitment to bringing back Sure Start centres, funding nursery and early years education properly, reversing almost all the Gove-era ideological changes to the curriculum and testing regimes, bringing back the arts, humanities, sport and extracurricular activities that schools can no longer afford or find time for, funding and reforming Send provision, investing properly in child and adolescent mental health services, abolishing Ofsted and replacing it with his majesty’s inspectors, introducing a fair salary system and, finally, abolishing multi-academy trusts and bringing all schools back under properly funded local education authority control.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2024/mar/14/how-labour-could-rescue-children-from-this-endless-series-of-educational-crises"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 18:38:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vulnerable man pleads with UK government to block extradition to US</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/law/2024/mar/15/diogo-santos-coelho-pleads-uk-block-us-extradition-cybercrime-raidforums</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Diogo Santos Coelho from Portugal faces a 52-year sentence for alleged cybercrime relating to RaidForums site&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A vulnerable autistic man is pleading with the UK government to block his extradition to the US on cybercrime charges where he faces a 52-year sentence for alleged offending that began when he was a child.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Diogo Santos Coelho, who has been assessed as at very high risk of suicide, said he had been groomed and exploited online by adults from the age of 14 into committing the alleged crimes, which relate to the website RaidForums.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In the UK and Ireland, &lt;a href="https://www.samaritans.org/"&gt;Samaritans&lt;/a&gt; can be contacted on freephone 116 123, or email &lt;a href="mailto:jo@samaritans.org"&gt;jo@samaritans.org&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="mailto:jo@samaritans.ie"&gt;jo@samaritans.ie&lt;/a&gt;. In the US, the &lt;a href="https://suicidepreventionlifeline.org/"&gt;National Suicide Prevention Lifeline&lt;/a&gt; is at 988 or chat for support. You can also text HOME to 741741 to connect with a crisis text line counselor. In Australia, the crisis support service &lt;a href="https://www.lifeline.org.au/"&gt;Lifeline&lt;/a&gt; is 13 11 14. Other international helplines can be found at &lt;a href="http://www.befrienders.org/"&gt;befrienders.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/law/2024/mar/15/diogo-santos-coelho-pleads-uk-block-us-extradition-cybercrime-raidforums"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 12:09:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Maybe everybody feels socially awkward’: the standups turning being autistic into a comedy superpower</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2024/mar/16/autism-comedy-superpower-fern-brady-pierre-novellie-joe-wells-charlie-george</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From Fern Brady to Hannah Gadsby, a host of comedians have discovered that they are autistic. What is it about standup that lends itself so well to neurodivergent people?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2020, Pierre Novellie was previewing an early version of&amp;nbsp; his standup show Why Can’t I&amp;nbsp;Just Enjoy Things? – things such as holidays and trips to the cinema (due to the “all the chewing and rustling packets”) – when he was interrupted by an audience member’s polite heckle. “He said: ‘You&amp;nbsp;sound like me,’” recalls Novellie. The&amp;nbsp;comedian asked what that meant. “He said: ‘I have Asperger’s – I think you have Asperger’s.’”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day, Novellie began seriously looking into the prospect that he was autistic (the term Asperger’s is no longer commonly used, partly because of its namesake’s Nazi affiliations, but&amp;nbsp;some autistic people still refer to it). He began taking multiple online tests, alternating between answering completely truthfully and “in the most normal, sociable way” he could, yet both approaches put him firmly above the threshold for autism. In 2022, he finally received a formal diagnosis – by&amp;nbsp;which point he’d realised that the title of Why Can’t I Just Enjoy Things? wasn’t rhetorical. “It turned out there was an answer: these were inherently autistic routines,” says Novellie (in&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;case of rustling packets, sound sensitivity is common in autistic people). “So that became the ending of&amp;nbsp;the show.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2024/mar/16/autism-comedy-superpower-fern-brady-pierre-novellie-joe-wells-charlie-george"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 14:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘A talented, goofy kid’: family of Ryan Gainer, autistic teen killed by police, speak out</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/mar/21/ryan-gainer-autistic-teen-police-killing-california</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shooting of 15-year-old ‘beautiful soul’ in California revives scrutiny on law enforcement abuse of youth with disabilities&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Ryan Gainer was diagnosed with autism as a toddler, he was nonverbal, and his family all learned sign language to communicate with him. But after the southern California boy learned how to speak at around age four, he was a “ball of energy” who never stopped talking, his older sister Rachel said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He loved saying “hi” to neighbors and strangers alike, and as a young teen was known as the student who greeted everyone with a “good morning” and a smile.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/mar/21/ryan-gainer-autistic-teen-police-killing-california"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 23:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Sensory Needs During the Holidays</title>
      <link>https://www.autismbc.ca/blog/sensory-friendly-holidays/</link>
      <description>This time of year is filled with an abundance of sensory stimuli unique to the holidays. The lights are brighter, the scents are richer, the food is special, and every day it seems like there is something else to do. For those of us with sensory processing challenges, it can easily become too much. Here are some tips from both a parent’s and autistic adult’s perspective to make this holiday season a little more sensory-friendly.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holidays</title>
      <link>https://www.autismspeaks.org/holidays</link>
      <description>Holidays can be both the best of times and the worst of times for autistic individuals and their families. Changes in routine, increased social demands, crowds and gatherings, new activities, sensory overloaded events, unfamiliar foods and other out-of-the-ordinary experiences can all present challenges.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>

