<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Autism News</title>
    <link>https://rcastonguay.github.io/autismfeeds/index.xml</link>
    <description>An RSS feed filtered by autism keywords.</description>
    <atom:link href="https://rcastonguay.github.io/autismfeeds/index.xml" rel="self"/>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 06:29:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Questioning the diagnosis of autism denies the difficulties people like me live with | Anthony Castle</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2024/mar/25/autism-diagnosis-ndis</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Being autistic doesn’t explain everything about me – but it helps make sense of my experiences&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;morning and afternoon news emails&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a man alongside me. He is well put-together, hand outstretched, deep voice. I stand in a room filled with competent people who look the part. I am there in my role, to get a story, but I have not been sleeping or eating. I feel as if I can’t breathe. The man is questioning me: Who are you? What do you do? I can’t answer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am covering a fundraising event as a journalist. I know why the man is questioning me – I have lost my name tag – but in this moment I am not able to answer. It has been one week since I was diagnosed with autism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed"&gt;Sign up for Guardian Australia’s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2024/mar/25/autism-diagnosis-ndis"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 01:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S6 Ep 7: Cat Burns, singer</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/audio/2024/mar/26/s6-ep-7-cat-burns-singer</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Platinum-selling singer songwriter Cat Burns cosies up with Grace for a warm plate of nosh and some deep chats. The biggest-selling British female artist of 2022, who won three Brit award nominations after her single Go went viral on TikTok, reveals how she went from shy schoolgirl to stadium gigs in just a few years. While Covid put an end to busking on the South Bank, it opened up another portal on social channels that sent Cat’s star on its rapid ascent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently diagnosed as autistic, Cat explains how her relationship with food thrives on predictability and consistency. Yet with a small recipe suggestion from her girlfriend, she had a lightbulb moment – opening up new possibilities. Cat says she doesn’t do small talk, which is more than OK; her big talk is just beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;New episodes of Comfort Eating with Grace Dent will be released every Tuesday&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/audio/2024/mar/26/s6-ep-7-cat-burns-singer"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 05:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Everybody has a breaking point’: how the climate crisis affects our brains</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2024/mar/27/everybody-has-a-breaking-point-how-the-climate-crisis-affects-our-brains</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are growing rates of anxiety, depression, ADHD, PTSD, Alzheimer’s and motor neurone disease related to rising temperatures and other extreme environmental changes?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In late October 2012, a category 3 hurricane howled into New York City with a force that would etch &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2022/oct/29/new-york-hurricane-sandy-climate-protest"&gt;its name into the annals of history&lt;/a&gt;. Superstorm Sandy transformed the city, inflicting more than $60bn in damage, killing dozens, and &lt;a href="https://www.nyc.gov/html/sirr/downloads/pdf/final_report/Ch_1_SandyImpacts_FINAL_singles.pdf"&gt;forcing&lt;/a&gt; 6,500 patients to be evacuated from hospitals and nursing homes. Yet in the case of one cognitive neuroscientist, the storm presented, darkly, an opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yoko Nomura had found herself at the centre of a natural experiment. Prior to the hurricane’s unexpected visit, Nomura – who teaches in the psychology department at Queens College, CUNY, as well as in the psychiatry department of the Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai – had meticulously assembled a research cohort of hundreds of expectant New York mothers. Her investigation, the &lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ije/article/46/5/1388/2907773"&gt;Stress in Pregnancy study&lt;/a&gt;, had aimed since 2009 to explore the potential imprint of prenatal stress on the unborn. Drawing on the evolving field of epigenetics, Nomura had sought to understand the ways in which environmental stressors could spur changes in gene expression, the likes of which were already known to influence the risk of specific childhood neurobehavioural outcomes such as autism, schizophrenia and &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2024/feb/21/adhd-may-have-been-an-evolutionary-advantage-research-suggests"&gt;attention deficit hyperactivity disorder&lt;/a&gt; (ADHD).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2024/mar/27/everybody-has-a-breaking-point-how-the-climate-crisis-affects-our-brains"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 05:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Female Character by Fern Brady review – moving account of undiagnosed autism</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2024/mar/29/strong-female-character-by-fern-brady-review-moving-account-of-undiagnosed-autism</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Scottish comedian narrates her traumatic experience of being ‘wired differently’ and why autism is so frequently missed in women&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the Scottish comedian Fern Brady phoned her father to say she had been diagnosed with autism, he was on his daily commute back from London. He said, “Oh right”, and began complaining about the traffic. Brady replied: “Well, they say autism can be inherited from one parent, so I guess that’s answered the question of which one.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Strong Female Character, written and narrated by Brady, and winner of the inaugural Nero award for nonfiction, documents the&amp;nbsp;turmoil of growing up with undiagnosed autism, during which she excelled academically but struggled with sensory overload and had violent outbursts that baffled her family, teachers and peers. After she began self-harming, her parents sent her to an adolescent psychiatric unit where she was a day patient. She was diagnosed with obsessive compulsive disorder, though she knew that wasn’t the whole story. It took until she was 34 to get an autism diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2024/mar/29/strong-female-character-by-fern-brady-review-moving-account-of-undiagnosed-autism"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 12:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UK’s black children ‘face cultural barriers’ in accessing help for autism and ADHD</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/education/2024/mar/31/uk-black-children-cultural-barriers-accessing-help-autism-adhd</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Campaigner Marsha Martin says ‘there is a lot of stigma within black community’ that prevents issues from being discussed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cultural barriers are preventing black children who are autistic or have attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) from accessing the help they need, the founder of a UK campaign for better support has said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of children with special educational needs (Send) routinely &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2024/feb/18/hundreds-of-children-with-special-needs-wait-a-year-for-support-in-england"&gt;wait&lt;/a&gt; for more than a year to get help as local authorities across England struggle to meet unprecedented need in a dire financial climate.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/education/2024/mar/31/uk-black-children-cultural-barriers-accessing-help-autism-adhd"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 08:30:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The sudden rise of AuDHD: what is behind the rocketing rates of this life-changing diagnosis?</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2024/apr/04/audhd-what-is-behind-rocketing-rates-life-changing-diagnosis</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just over a decade ago, autism and ADHD were thought to be mutually exclusive. But in recent years, all that has changed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He had beaten more than 19,000&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;applicants for a place at medical school, yet Khurram Sadiq was now bunking off his hospital shifts. The 19-year-old felt inexplicably anxious around strangers on the wards and was hiding from his own&amp;nbsp;patients.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;During lectures he couldn’t focus on what he was being taught. He deemed himself “a goof, a dunce” in contrast to his peers. Sadiq couldn’t motivate himself to revise for his exams and instead found himself panic reading textbooks in the final days. He passed his undergraduate pre-medical exams by the skin of his teeth.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That was 30 years ago. In the decades since, Dr Sadiq has qualified as a consultant psychiatrist, been diagnosed with both autism and attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD),&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;specialised in autism and ADHD psychiatry and met hundreds of patients with struggles similar to his. He is now trying to spread what was once an unbelievable message: that both autism and ADHD can coexist in the same person&amp;nbsp;simultaneously.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Just over a decade ago, the two conditions were considered to be mutually exclusive, with the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, often referred to as “psychiatry’s bible”, stating that the diagnosis of one &lt;a href="https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__www.spectrumnews.org_news_new-2Drules-2Dallow-2Djoint-2Ddiagnosis-2Dof-2Dautism-2Dattention-2Ddeficit_&amp;amp;amp;d=DwMFaQ&amp;amp;amp;c=euGZstcaTDllvimEN8b7jXrwqOf-v5A_CdpgnVfiiMM&amp;amp;amp;r=WkcRK3Crq-fGerXGdpVAxhQa54b7o8GzP26Di4ZpJJo&amp;amp;amp;m=WBMiMfilEOObsC96W7gW8PJ296Ba5mN66TYhc3Oso7RLLZzLWDcWXuAQODmgeOdG&amp;amp;amp;s=HQkfxBMBQixv0NPtxazwjzfV3TZBizDZC2ZHhWtsJlc&amp;amp;amp;e="&gt;precluded the existence&lt;/a&gt; of the other.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;This wasn’t revised until 2013. “It led to a fork in the road,” says Dr Jessica Eccles, spokesperson for the Royal College of Psychiatrists. “Not only for clinical practice, but also for research and public understanding of these conditions.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Now some specialists believe that the coexistence of both conditions is not just possible, but frequent. &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3441928/"&gt;One study&lt;/a&gt; by researchers at Duke University found that up to half of people diagnosed as autistic also exhibit ADHD symptoms, and that characteristics of autism are present in two-thirds of people with ADHD. “My clinical experience suggests it’s more than three-quarters in both directions,” adds Dr Eccles.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Online, the idea that autism and ADHD can coexist is so widely accepted that it has spawned its own label – “AuDHD” – and a groundswell of people who say they recognise its oxymoronic nature, perpetual internal war and rollercoaster of needs. There are tens of thousands of people in AuDHD self-help forums, and millions more watching AuDHD&amp;nbsp;videos.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Some of those videos come from Samantha Stein, a British YouTuber. “The fact that you can have both [autism and ADHD] at the same time is kind of paradoxical in nature,” she admits. “You think: ‘How can you be extremely rigid and need routines and structure, but also be completely incapable&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;maintaining a routine and structure?’”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The 38-year-old started making videos on autism after her diagnosis in 2019, then began covering AuDHD after learning that she also had ADHD. “I realised that autistic adults – especially those who are diagnosed late in life – more often than not seem to have ADHD as well,” says Stein. Her first video on the subject, “&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/pMx1DnSn-eg?si=iAHmDB7SkXXe8Kqf"&gt;5 signs you have ADHD and autism&lt;/a&gt;”, has now been viewed more than 2m times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some critics like to describe ADHD – and more recently autism – as a “fashionable” diagnosis, a misinformed excuse for life’s struggles. It’s almost inevitable that the new AuDHD label will cause a similar backlash. To see just how misguided this is, we must first understand both autism and ADHD. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Both are lifelong neurodevelopmental conditions that affect how people think, perceive the world and interact with others, according to &lt;a href="https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__embracingcomplexity.org.uk_news_special-2Dinterest-2Dresearch-2Dgroup&amp;amp;amp;d=DwMFaQ&amp;amp;amp;c=euGZstcaTDllvimEN8b7jXrwqOf-v5A_CdpgnVfiiMM&amp;amp;amp;r=WkcRK3Crq-fGerXGdpVAxhQa54b7o8GzP26Di4ZpJJo&amp;amp;amp;m=WBMiMfilEOObsC96W7gW8PJ296Ba5mN66TYhc3Oso7RLLZzLWDcWXuAQODmgeOdG&amp;amp;amp;s=8gEk4PKxS5wTd5SBZNOLy2v6utyjb5gfNmnH7S4DsYA&amp;amp;amp;e="&gt;Embracing Complexity&lt;/a&gt;, an umbrella group of organisations that research neurodiversity.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2024/apr/04/audhd-what-is-behind-rocketing-rates-life-changing-diagnosis"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 04:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NHS faces ‘avalanche’ of demand for autism and ADHD services, thinktank warns</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/apr/04/nhs-faces-avalanche-of-demand-for-autism-and-adhd-services-thinktank-warns</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nuffield Trust says system for treatment is ‘obsolete’ as number of patients in England awaiting assessment hits record high&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NHS is experiencing an “avalanche of need” over autism and attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD), but the system in place to cope with surging demand for assessments and treatments is “obsolete”, a health thinktank has warned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There must be a “radical rethink” of how people with the conditions are cared for in England if the health service is to meet the rapidly expanding need for services, according to the Nuffield Trust.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2024/apr/04/nhs-faces-avalanche-of-demand-for-autism-and-adhd-services-thinktank-warns"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 07:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autism makes travel a challenge. Here’s how I learned to cope</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2024/apr/22/autism-makes-travel-a-challenge-heres-how-i-learned-to-cope</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Busy places and unexpected events used to send me into meltdown on holiday. An autism diagnosis helped me to adapt my plans and rediscover the joy of travelling&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wandering hand-in-hand through the medieval streets of Bologna, my boyfriend and I were in awe of the sweeping porticoes and distinctive rust-red brickwork of the city. It was our first holiday together. We’d wanted to find somewhere beyond the obvious that would marry our respective interests in architecture and history. Bologna was the perfect fit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We admired the &lt;a href="https://www.bolognawelcome.com/en/places/religious-buildings/church-of-santa-maria-della-vita"&gt;Church of Santa Maria della Vita&lt;/a&gt;, with its imposing baroque interior, lavishly decorated in colourful frescoes and marble carvings. We caught a little red and blue express train up into the hills to the &lt;a href="https://www.bolognawelcome.com/en/places/religious-buildings/sanctuary-of-san-luca-eng"&gt;Santuario della Madonna di San Luca&lt;/a&gt;, and climbed the bell tower of the &lt;a href="https://www.bolognawelcome.com/en/places/religious-buildings/basilica-of-san-petronio-eng"&gt;Basilica di San Petronio&lt;/a&gt; for panoramic views across the city.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2024/apr/22/autism-makes-travel-a-challenge-heres-how-i-learned-to-cope"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 06:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘People like Connor are still left to die in squalor’: the truth, joy and tragedy behind Laughing Boy</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2024/apr/22/laughing-boy-connor-sparrowhawk-sarah-ryan-stephen-unwin</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A decade after her autistic son Connor Sparrowhawk died in a specialist NHS facility, Sara Ryan’s campaign to reveal the truth about what happened is coming to the stage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a bare rehearsal space near Southwark tube station, south London, 11 people are in the process of forming a circle, ready for a read-through of a&amp;nbsp;new play. On the top of a&amp;nbsp;nearby piano is a small mountain of&amp;nbsp;tea, coffee and biscuits; for two or three minutes, everything is drowned out by the wheezing and groaning of a&amp;nbsp;very loud kettle. The mood is upbeat and energetic; everyone here seems to be happily immersed in the strange magic of turning the script resting on their laps into something full of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is quite a job. The play in question, Laughing Boy, encompasses both everyday joy and the most awful kind of sadness: some of it is about life at its most intense, but its defining event is a senseless and unimaginably tragic death. It also pulls off the rare achievement of being political – at least with a small “p” – but also full of&amp;nbsp;human emotion. The preamble to the script speaks volumes: “It’s a terrible story,” it says, “but it must be&amp;nbsp;performed with optimism, laughter, satire and energy.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2024/apr/22/laughing-boy-connor-sparrowhawk-sarah-ryan-stephen-unwin"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 08:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With her Netflix comedy special Autistic Bikini Queen, Fern Brady is a cynic to savour</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2024/apr/23/fern-brady-autistic-bikini-queen-is-the-work-of-a-cynic-to-savour</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The huge success of her memoir has turbocharged the Scottish comedian’s career, with midlife, Catholicism and marriage in her withering sights&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cynicism is now and then expressed about the phenomenon of comedians writing books. Rare is the instance of a comic finding more success on the page than at the microphone. Step forward, then, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2022/jan/24/everything-ends-up-about-death-and-shagging-fern-brady-on-comedy-autism-and-intrusive-thoughts"&gt;Fern Brady&lt;/a&gt;, whose memoir &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2024/mar/29/strong-female-character-by-fern-brady-review-moving-account-of-undiagnosed-autism"&gt;Strong Female Character&lt;/a&gt;, about her experience as an undiagnosed autistic woman, has met with awards and widespread acclaim – and seems to have turbocharged the Scot’s standup career too. One assumes the book’s success was a factor in securing Brady gigs at next month’s &lt;a href="https://www.netflixisajokefest.com/"&gt;Netflix Is a Joke&lt;/a&gt; festival in Los Angeles, and this new special on the streamer too – whose title, Autistic Bikini Queen, invites fans of the memoir to come savour more of the same.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is that what they’ll get? Well, they’ll certainly get a potent hit of the 37-year-old’s unsentimental personality, as Brady – filmed at a Bristol performance last year – launches into spiky riffs on marriage and relationships. There’s not much, or at least not directly, on her experience of autism. The topic is efficiently dispatched in the opening five minutes with a droll gag about the idea that her neurodiversity is “a superpower”. There’s also a joke about her undiagnosed condition revealing itself in Brady’s squeamishness about touching or hugging her mum, which sounded to this viewer less like a symptom of autism than of Scottishness.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2024/apr/23/fern-brady-autistic-bikini-queen-is-the-work-of-a-cynic-to-savour"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 15:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the rise of autism and ADHD fractured Australia’s schools</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/apr/29/how-the-rise-of-autism-and-adhd-fractured-australias-schools</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost a million Australian schoolchildren now have a disability – that’s one in four enrolments. Parents, teachers and advocates say education is at crisis point&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/apr/29/revealed-private-school-students-reap-thousands-more-than-public-students-in-disability-funding"&gt;Revealed: Private school students reap thousands more than public students in disability funding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Analysis: &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/apr/29/why-the-guardian-is-investigating-the-deep-failings-in-australias-school-system"&gt;Why the Guardian is investigating the deep failings in Australia’s school system&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every morning before school, Emerson Cook would ask his mum to check the weather. If it was raining she knew her then five-year-old would be anxious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“He was always worried about rain,” Alicia Cook says. “And if the weather forecast was rain, I would be anxious too …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed"&gt;Sign up for Guardian Australia’s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/apr/29/how-the-rise-of-autism-and-adhd-fractured-australias-schools"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 15:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Students as young as five with disabilities disproportionately suspended from Australia’s schools</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/may/01/australia-schools-students-with-disabilities-disproportionately-suspended</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Guardian Australia data analysis shows suspensions are increasing in most states. Students with disabilities are overrepresented&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/apr/29/how-the-rise-of-autism-and-adhd-fractured-australias-schools"&gt;How the rise of autism and ADHD fractured Australia’s schools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Analysis: &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/apr/29/why-the-guardian-is-investigating-the-deep-failings-in-australias-school-system"&gt;Why the Guardian is investigating the deep failings in Australia’s school system&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thousands of students with a disability, including those as young as five, are receiving repeated suspensions from Australian schools amid calls from advocates for an overhaul of the education system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Guardian Australia analysis of school suspension data shows the number of students being suspended from schools is rising in most states, including among primary school aged students.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed"&gt;Sign up for Guardian Australia’s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/may/01/australia-schools-students-with-disabilities-disproportionately-suspended"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 15:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six-year-old student restrained in infant high chair at NSW school, family claims</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/may/02/six-year-old-student-restrained-in-infant-high-chair-at-nsw-school-family-claims</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The boy, who has autism and Down syndrome, was photographed in the restraint for a social media post, his guardian says&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/apr/29/why-the-guardian-is-investigating-the-deep-failings-in-australias-school-system"&gt;Why the Guardian is investigating the deep failings in Australia’s school system&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/may/01/australia-schools-students-with-disabilities-disproportionately-suspended"&gt;Students as young as five with disabilities disproportionately suspended from Australia’s schools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;morning and afternoon news emails&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A six-year-old boy &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/apr/29/how-the-rise-of-autism-and-adhd-fractured-australias-schools"&gt;with autism&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/downs-syndrome"&gt;Down syndrome&lt;/a&gt; was strapped into an infant’s high chair at a New South Wales primary school regularly over an eight-month period, his family allege, with the case now the subject of a complaint to the Australian Human Rights Commission.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Neville Williams’ aunt and guardian, Karla Bedford, said she first learned that the six-year-old was being physically restrained at Tingha public school in northern NSW after the school posted a photo of him in the chair on social media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=copyembed"&gt;Sign up for Guardian Australia’s free morning and afternoon email newsletters for your daily news roundup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2024/may/02/six-year-old-student-restrained-in-infant-high-chair-at-nsw-school-family-claims"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I’m going to be blunt: our neurotypical school system is the problem | Elly Desmarchelier</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/commentisfree/2024/may/02/im-going-to-be-blunt-our-neurotypical-school-system-is-the-problem</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Classrooms must be places of learning not conflict, where each child’s individual needs are understood and supported &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s me, hi, I’m the problem, it’s me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As an autistic person, that’s certainly the way it feels at the moment. Autism seems to be to blame for every issue.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/commentisfree/2024/may/02/im-going-to-be-blunt-our-neurotypical-school-system-is-the-problem"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carolann Jackson obituary</title>
      <link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/may/05/carolann-jackson-obituary</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend Carolann Jackson, who has died aged 80, was a campaigner and advocate on behalf of people with Asperger syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the first part of her adult life she worked in the music business, managing bands. But her focus changed after the birth of her daughter, Nita. Early on, Carolann noticed that her daughter appeared to behave differently to other children of her age.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/article/2024/may/05/carolann-jackson-obituary"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 15:47:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meeting Sensory Needs During the Holidays</title>
      <link>https://www.autismbc.ca/blog/sensory-friendly-holidays/</link>
      <description>This time of year is filled with an abundance of sensory stimuli unique to the holidays. The lights are brighter, the scents are richer, the food is special, and every day it seems like there is something else to do. For those of us with sensory processing challenges, it can easily become too much. Here are some tips from both a parent’s and autistic adult’s perspective to make this holiday season a little more sensory-friendly.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holidays</title>
      <link>https://www.autismspeaks.org/holidays</link>
      <description>Holidays can be both the best of times and the worst of times for autistic individuals and their families. Changes in routine, increased social demands, crowds and gatherings, new activities, sensory overloaded events, unfamiliar foods and other out-of-the-ordinary experiences can all present challenges.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>

